<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>phd-icn | Novel visual computations</title>
    <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/tags/phd-icn/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://laurentperrinet.github.io/tags/phd-icn/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>phd-icn</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>This material is presented to ensure timely dissemination of scholarly and technical work. Copyright and all rights therein are retained by authors or by other copyright holders. All persons copying this information are expected to adhere to the terms and constraints invoked by each author&#39;s copyright. In most cases, these works may not be reposted without the explicit permission of the copyright holder. 
This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 3.0 Unported License Please note that multiple distribution, publication or commercial usage of copyrighted papers included in this website would require submission of a permission request addressed to the journal in which the paper appeared. </copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/img/hulk.png</url>
      <title>phd-icn</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/tags/phd-icn/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhD ICN (2017 / 2021)</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/grant/phd-icn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/grant/phd-icn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://neuro-marseille.org/en/phd-program-en/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Ph.D. program in Integrative and Clinical Neuroscience&lt;/a&gt; (Aix-Marseille University) is offering in 2017 three Ph.D. scholarships to Master students graduated from highly ranked international universities (outside France). We were awarded with one PhD position for Angelo Franciosini at the &amp;ldquo;Institut de Neurosciences de la Timone&amp;rdquo; (team &amp;ldquo;Inference and Visual Behavior&amp;rdquo;), CNRS, Marseille (France) to study trajectories in natural images and the sensory processing of contours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;##Funding&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project is funded by the Aix-Marseille Université, which was awarded the prestigious status of &amp;ldquo;Excellence Initiative&amp;rdquo; (A*MIDEX) by the French Government and considering interdisciplinary studies as one of its main axes of growth. Within this program, the PhD fellow will sign a three-year work contract. They will enroll the ICN PhD program offering personalized follow-up to the students, a wide spectrum of scientific and professional training activities including specialized courses and career development activities and interactions with multi-disciplinary researchers at Aix-Marseille University and top world-wide visiting speakers, in a vibrant international community of students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;acknowledgement&#34;&gt;Acknowledgement&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work was supported by the Ph.D. program in Integrative and Clinical Neuroscience (formerly &amp;ldquo;Ph.D. program in Integrative and Clinical Neuroscience&amp;rdquo;). It received funding by the Aix-Marseille Université through the prestigious status of &amp;ldquo;Excellence Initiative&amp;rdquo; (A*MIDEX) awarded by the French Government.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
