<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Novel computational paradigms for vision on Novel computational paradigms for vision</title>
    <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Novel computational paradigms for vision on Novel computational paradigms for vision</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This material is presented to ensure timely dissemination of scholarly and technical work. Copyright and all rights therein are retained by authors or by other copyright holders. All persons copying this information are expected to adhere to the terms and constraints invoked by each author&#39;s copyright. In most cases, these works may not be reposted without the explicit permission of the copyright holder.
&lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Creative Commons License&#34; style=&#34;border-width:0&#34; src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/3.0/88x31.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This work is licensed under a &lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 3.0 Unported License&lt;/a&gt;
Please note that multiple distribution, publication or commercial usage of copyrighted papers included in this website would require submission of a permission request addressed to the journal in which the paper appeared.
</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Des illusions aux hallucinations visuelles: une porte sur la perception</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/talk/2019-04-18_jnlf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/talk/2019-04-18_jnlf/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speed-Selectivity in Retinal Ganglion Cells is Sharpened by Broad Spatial Frequency, Naturalistic Stimuli</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/ravello-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/ravello-19/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;dès-la-rétine-le-système-visuel-préfère-des-images-naturelles&#34;&gt;Dès la rétine, le système visuel préfère des images naturelles&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dans la rétine, au premier étage du traitement de l&amp;rsquo;image visuelle, on peut obtenir des représentations extrêmement fines. Une collaboration entre des chercheurs français et chiliens a permis de mettre en évidence que, dans la rétine de rongeurs, une représentation de la vitesse de l&amp;rsquo;image visuelle est précisément codée. Dans cette collaboration pluridisciplinaire, l&amp;rsquo;utilisation d&amp;rsquo;un modèle du fonctionnement de la rétine a permis de générer un nouveau type de stimuli visuels qui a révélé des résultats expérimentaux surprenants.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;fr&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Travail collaboratif et multi-disciplinaire entre &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/cesarravello?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@cesarravello&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurentperrinet?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@laurentperrinet&lt;/a&gt; María José Escobar et &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/APalacio_s?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@APalacio_s&lt;/a&gt; librement disponible sur &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/SciReports?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@SciReports&lt;/a&gt; - merci à  l&amp;#39;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/AgenceRecherche?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@AgenceRecherche&lt;/a&gt; pour l&amp;#39;aide financière et à &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/CNRS?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@CNRS&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/CNRS_dr12?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@CNRS_dr12&lt;/a&gt; + &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/univamu?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@univamu&lt;/a&gt; pour l&amp;#39;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/InstitutDeNeurosciencesDeLaTimone?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#InstitutDeNeurosciencesDeLaTimone&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/YixRfpCrT3&#34;&gt;https://t.co/YixRfpCrT3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; laurentperrinet (@laurentperrinet) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurentperrinet/status/1092139540788244480?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;February 3, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;La rétine est la première étape du traitement visuel, aux capacités étonnantes. À la différence d&amp;rsquo;un simple capteur comme ceux qu’on trouve dans les appareils photographiques numériques, ce mince tissu neuronal est un système complexe et encore largement méconnu. Une meilleure connaissance de cette structure est essentielle pour la construction de capteurs du futur efficaces et économes -par exemple ceux qui équiperont les futures voitures autonomes- mais aussi pour mieux comprendre des pathologies comme la Déficience Maculaire Liée à l&amp;rsquo;Age (DMLA). Une des facettes méconnues de la rétine est sa capacité à détecter des mouvements et cet article permet de mieux comprendre une partie des mécanismes en jeu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;New study on speed selectivity in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/retina?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#retina&lt;/a&gt; showing that a majority of neurons prefer natural-like stimuli. Collaborative and multi-disciplinary work with &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/cesarravello?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@cesarravello&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurentperrinet?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@laurentperrinet&lt;/a&gt; María José Escobar and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/APalacio_s?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@APalacio_s&lt;/a&gt; available with &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/SciReports?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@SciReports&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/Vb7GoRxjoT&#34;&gt;https://t.co/Vb7GoRxjoT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Adrian Palacios (@APalacio_s) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/APalacio_s/status/1092200890377879552?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;February 3, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Retinal cell preference for natural-like stimuli. Very elegant work by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/APalacio_s?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@APalacio_s&lt;/a&gt; et al. &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/retina?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#retina&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/neuroscience?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#neuroscience&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/decoding?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#decoding&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/3xNWaZd5x6&#34;&gt;https://t.co/3xNWaZd5x6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Andres Canales-Johnson (@canalesjohnson) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/canalesjohnson/status/1092211339311923201?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;February 4, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conciliant modélisation et neurophysiologie, cette étude a permis de faire des prédictions sur le traitement de l&amp;rsquo;information rétinienne et en particulier de générer des textures synthétiques qui sont optimales pour ces modèles (voir film). Les enregistrements effectués sur la rétine de rongeurs diurnes Octodon degus ont ensuite permis de mesurer la sélectivité à la vitesse mais aussi de valider une nouvelle fois ces modèles en reconstruisant l&amp;rsquo;image d&amp;rsquo;entrée à partir de l&amp;rsquo;activité neurale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Le résultat le plus inattendu est la différence de sélectivité de certaines classes de neurones rétiniens par rapport à la complexité du stimulus présenté. En effet, la représentation de la vitesse est relativement peu précise si on utilise des réseaux de lignes (&amp;ldquo;Grating&amp;rdquo;), comme cela est d&amp;rsquo;habitude réalisé dans la plupart des expériences neurophysiologiques. Au contraire, elle devient plus précise si on utilise comme signaux visuels des textures artificielles ressemblant à des nuages en mouvement (&amp;ldquo;MC Narrow&amp;rdquo;). En particulier, plus cette texture est complexe, plus la représentation est précise (&amp;ldquo;MC Broad&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;fr&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/R%C3%A9sultatScientifique?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#RésultatScientifique&lt;/a&gt; 🔍| Dès la &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/r%C3%A9tine?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#rétine&lt;/a&gt;, le système &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/visuel?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#visuel&lt;/a&gt; préfère des images naturelles&lt;br&gt;▶️ &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/BBY2IpGum6&#34;&gt;https://t.co/BBY2IpGum6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;📕 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/SciReports?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@SciReports&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/5mULuWTp3N&#34;&gt;https://t.co/5mULuWTp3N&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;🤝 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/CNRS?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@CNRS&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/CNRS_dr12?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@CNRS_dr12&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/univamu?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@univamu&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/InstitutDeNeurosciencesDeLaTimone?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#InstitutDeNeurosciencesDeLaTimone&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/LaurentPerrinet?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#LaurentPerrinet&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/34R1URHUic&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/34R1URHUic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Biologie au CNRS (@INSB_CNRS) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/INSB_CNRS/status/1091392027848294401?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;February 1, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Speed-Selectivity in Retinal Ganglion Cells is Sharpened by Broad Spatial Frequency, Naturalistic Stimuli. Beautiful article in Scientific Reports on an original animal model, the diurnal rodent Octodon degus. &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/BdzyzEVYnX&#34;&gt;https://t.co/BdzyzEVYnX&lt;/a&gt; (open access) &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/1UaoMYTFd2&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/1UaoMYTFd2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Stéphane Deny (@StephaneDeny) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/StephaneDeny/status/1090452532223045632?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;January 30, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ces textures complexes sont plus proches des images naturellement observées et ces résultats montrent donc que dès la rétine, le système visuel est particulièrement adapté à des stimulations naturelles. Ce résultat devrait pouvoir s&amp;rsquo;étendre à des textures encore plus complexes et encore plus proches d&amp;rsquo;images naturelles, mais aussi pouvoir se généraliser à d&amp;rsquo;autres aires visuelles plus complexes, comme le cortex visuel primaire, et à d&amp;rsquo;autres espèces.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;http://www4.cnrs-dir.fr/insb/z-outils/images/site/recherche/publis/2019/article-perrinet.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; &gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;our une cellule représentative, on montre ici la réponse au cours du temps sous forme d&amp;rsquo;impulsions pour différentes présentations (Trial) ainsi que la moyenne de cette réponse (Firing rate). Les différentes colonnes représentent différentes vitesses des stimulations sur la rétine. Les différentes lignes sont différentes stimulations. En bleu, une stimulation classique sous forme de réseaux de lignes (« Grating »). En vert et Orange, la réponse à une texture progressivement plus complexe (de « Mc Narrow » à « MC Broad »). Si les réponses aux différents stimulations sont en moyenne similaires, elles sont variables d’essai en essai et une analyse statistique a permis de montrer que dans la majorité des cellules, les réponses sont d&amp;rsquo;autant plus précises que la stimulation est complexe. © Cesar Ravello&lt;/h4&gt;
  
&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;











  


&lt;video controls &gt;
  &lt;source src=&#34;video_perrinet.mp4&#34; type=&#34;video/mp4&#34;&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;
Cette vidéo montre les trois classes de stimulations utilisées dans cette étude. En plus des réseaux sinusoïdaux (“Grating”) qui sont classiquement utilisés en neurosciences, cette étude a utilisé des textures aléatoires (Motion Clouds (MC)) qui sont inspirées de modèles du traitement visuel. Ils permettent en particulier de manipuler des paramètres visuels critiques comme la variété de fréquences spatiales qui sont superposées: soit unique (“Grating”), fine (“MC Narrow”), soit plus large (“MC Broad”). Ces vidéos ont été directement projetées sur des rétines posées sur des grilles d’électrodes qui permettent de mesurer l’activité neurale (voir figure). © Laurent Perrinet / Cesar Ravello&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reinforcement effects in anticipatory smooth eye movements</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/damasse-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/damasse-18/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Example Page</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/tutorial/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/tutorial/example/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial, I&amp;rsquo;ll share my top 10 tips for getting started with Academic:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tip-1&#34;&gt;Tip 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tip-2&#34;&gt;Tip 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Suppressive waves disambiguate the representation of long-range apparent motion in awake monkey V1</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/chemla-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/chemla-18/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The flash-lag effect as a motion-based predictive shift</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/khoei-masson-perrinet-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/khoei-masson-perrinet-17/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;[header]
  image = &amp;ldquo;header.png&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;visual-illusions-their-origin-lies-in-prediction&#34;&gt;Visual illusions: their origin lies in prediction&lt;/h1&gt;




&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;flash_lag.gif&#34; /&gt;



&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; &gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;&lt;em&gt;Flash-Lag Effect.&lt;/em&gt; When a visual stimulus moves along a continuous trajectory, it may be seen ahead of its veridical position with respect to an unpredictable event such as a punctuate flash. This illusion tells us something important about the visual system: contrary to classical computers, neural activity travels at a relatively slow speed. It is largely accepted that the resulting delays cause this perceived spatial lag of the flash. Still, after several decades of debates, there is no consensus regarding the underlying mechanisms.&lt;/h4&gt;
  
&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Researchers from the Timone Institute of Neurosciences bring a new theoretical hypothesis on a visual illusion discovered at the beginning of the 20th century. This illusion remained misunderstood while it poses fundamental questions about how our brains represent events in space and time. This study published on January 26, 2017 in the journal PLOS Computational Biology, shows that the solution lies in the predictive mechanisms intrinsic to the neural processing of information.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;New Research: The Flash-Lag Effect as a Motion-Based Predictive Shift &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/K3KWPO8l4a&#34;&gt;https://t.co/K3KWPO8l4a&lt;/a&gt; Khoei et al. &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/vision?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#vision&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/motion?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#motion&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/neuralnetworks?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#neuralnetworks&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/RElm4Qqo58&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/RElm4Qqo58&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; PLOS Comp Biol (@PLOSCompBiol) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/PLOSCompBiol/status/829354100273745920?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;February 8, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Visual illusions are still popular: in a quasi-magical way, they can make objects appear where they are not expected&amp;hellip; They are also excellent opportunities to question the constraints of our perceptual system. Many illusions are based on motion, such as the flash-lag effect. Observe a luminous dot that moves along a rectilinear trajectory. If a second light dot is flashed very briefly just above the first, the moving point will always be perceived in front of the flash while they are vertically aligned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Processing visual information takes time and even if these delays are remarkably short, they are not negligible and the nervous system must compensate them. For an object that moves predictably, the neural network can infer its most probable position taking into account this processing time. For the flash, however, this prediction can not be established because its appearance is unpredictable. Thus, while the two targets are aligned on the retina at the time of the flash, the position of the moving object is anticipated by the brain to compensate for the processing time: it is this differentiated treatment that causes the flash-lag effect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The researchers show that this hypothesis also makes it possible to explain the cases where this illusion does not work: for example if the flash appears at the end of the moving dot&amp;rsquo;s trajectory or if the target reverses its path in an unexpected way. In this work, the major innovation is to use the accuracy of information in the dynamics of the model. Thus, the corrected position of the moving target is calculated by combining the sensory flux with the internal representation of the trajectory, both of which exist in the form of probability distributions. To manipulate the trajectory is to change the precision and therefore the relative weight of these two information when they are optimally combined in order to know where an object is at the present time. The researchers propose to call parodiction (from the ancient Greek paron, the present) this new theory that joins Bayesian inference with taking into account neuronal delays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the simplicity of this solution, parodiction has elements that may seem counter-intuitive. Indeed, in this model, the physical world is considered &amp;ldquo;hidden&amp;rdquo;, that is to say, it can only be guessed by our sensations and our experience. The role of visual perception is then to deliver to our central nervous system the most likely information despite the different sources of noise, ambiguity and time delays. According to the authors of this publication, the visual treatment would consist in a &amp;ldquo;simulation&amp;rdquo; of the visual world projected at the present time, even before the visual information can actually modulate, confirm or cancel this simulation. This hypothesis, which seems to belong to &amp;ldquo;science fiction&amp;rdquo;, is being tested with more detailed and biologically plausible hierarchical neural network models that should allow us to better understand the mysteries underlying our perception. Visual illusions have still the power to amaze us!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;New from Khoei et al. The Flash-Lag Effect as a &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/Motion?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#Motion&lt;/a&gt;-Based Predictive Shift &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/K3KWPO8l4a&#34;&gt;https://t.co/K3KWPO8l4a&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/neuralnetworks?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#neuralnetworks&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/iWsd9nK5qp&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/iWsd9nK5qp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; PLOS Comp Biol (@PLOSCompBiol) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/PLOSCompBiol/status/829474896023474176?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;February 8, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Differential response of the retinal neural code with respect to the sparseness of natural images</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/ravello-16-droplets/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/ravello-16-droplets/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biologically-inspired characterization of sparseness in natural images</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/perrinet-16-euvip/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/perrinet-16-euvip/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Operant reinforcement versus reward expectancy: effects on anticipatory eye movements</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/damasse-16-vss/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/damasse-16-vss/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>External Project</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/project/tout-public/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/project/tout-public/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internal Project</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/project/internal-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/project/internal-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Duis posuere tellus ac convallis placerat. Proin tincidunt magna sed ex sollicitudin condimentum. Sed ac faucibus dolor, scelerisque sollicitudin nisi. Cras purus urna, suscipit quis sapien eu, pulvinar tempor diam. Quisque risus orci, mollis id ante sit amet, gravida egestas nisl. Sed ac tempus magna. Proin in dui enim. Donec condimentum, sem id dapibus fringilla, tellus enim condimentum arcu, nec volutpat est felis vel metus. Vestibulum sit amet erat at nulla eleifend gravida.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nullam vel molestie justo. Curabitur vitae efficitur leo. In hac habitasse platea dictumst. Sed pulvinar mauris dui, eget varius purus congue ac. Nulla euismod, lorem vel elementum dapibus, nunc justo porta mi, sed tempus est est vel tellus. Nam et enim eleifend, laoreet sem sit amet, elementum sem. Morbi ut leo congue, maximus velit ut, finibus arcu. In et libero cursus, rutrum risus non, molestie leo. Nullam congue quam et volutpat malesuada. Sed risus tortor, pulvinar et dictum nec, sodales non mi. Phasellus lacinia commodo laoreet. Nam mollis, erat in feugiat consectetur, purus eros egestas tellus, in auctor urna odio at nibh. Mauris imperdiet nisi ac magna convallis, at rhoncus ligula cursus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cras aliquam rhoncus ipsum, in hendrerit nunc mattis vitae. Duis vitae efficitur metus, ac tempus leo. Cras nec fringilla lacus. Quisque sit amet risus at ipsum pharetra commodo. Sed aliquam mauris at consequat eleifend. Praesent porta, augue sed viverra bibendum, neque ante euismod ante, in vehicula justo lorem ac eros. Suspendisse augue libero, venenatis eget tincidunt ut, malesuada at lorem. Donec vitae bibendum arcu. Aenean maximus nulla non pretium iaculis. Quisque imperdiet, nulla in pulvinar aliquet, velit quam ultrices quam, sit amet fringilla leo sem vel nunc. Mauris in lacinia lacus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suspendisse a tincidunt lacus. Curabitur at urna sagittis, dictum ante sit amet, euismod magna. Sed rutrum massa id tortor commodo, vitae elementum turpis tempus. Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Aenean purus turpis, venenatis a ullamcorper nec, tincidunt et massa. Integer posuere quam rutrum arcu vehicula imperdiet. Mauris ullamcorper quam vitae purus congue, quis euismod magna eleifend. Vestibulum semper vel augue eget tincidunt. Fusce eget justo sodales, dapibus odio eu, ultrices lorem. Duis condimentum lorem id eros commodo, in facilisis mauris scelerisque. Morbi sed auctor leo. Nullam volutpat a lacus quis pharetra. Nulla congue rutrum magna a ornare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aliquam in turpis accumsan, malesuada nibh ut, hendrerit justo. Cum sociis natoque penatibus et magnis dis parturient montes, nascetur ridiculus mus. Quisque sed erat nec justo posuere suscipit. Donec ut efficitur arcu, in malesuada neque. Nunc dignissim nisl massa, id vulputate nunc pretium nec. Quisque eget urna in risus suscipit ultricies. Pellentesque odio odio, tincidunt in eleifend sed, posuere a diam. Nam gravida nisl convallis semper elementum. Morbi vitae felis faucibus, vulputate orci placerat, aliquet nisi. Aliquam erat volutpat. Maecenas sagittis pulvinar purus, sed porta quam laoreet at.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Academic: the website designer for Hugo</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/etiennerey/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/etiennerey/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Academic&lt;/strong&gt; makes it easy to create a beautiful website for free using Markdown. Customize anything on your site with widgets, themes, and language packs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow our easy &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/install/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;step by step guide&lt;/a&gt; to learn how to build your own free website with Academic. &lt;a href=&#34;https://academic-demo.netlify.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Check out the personal demo&lt;/a&gt; or the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;business demo&lt;/a&gt; of what you&amp;rsquo;ll get in less than 10 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;View the documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://discuss.gohugo.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ask a question&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/issues&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Request a feature or report a bug&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updating? View the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/update/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Update Guide&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/updates/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Release Notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support development of Academic:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://paypal.me/cushen&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Donate a coffee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.patreon.com/cushen&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Become a backer on Patreon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.redbubble.com/people/neutreno/works/34387919-academic&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Decorate your laptop or journal with an Academic sticker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://academic.threadless.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wear the T-shirt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/master/academic.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Key features:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easily manage various content including homepage, blog posts, publications, talks, and projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extensible via &lt;strong&gt;color themes&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;widgets/plugins&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write in &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Markdown&lt;/a&gt; for easy formatting and code highlighting, with &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikibooks.org/wiki/LaTeX/Mathematics&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;LaTeX&lt;/a&gt; for mathematical expressions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Social/academic network linking, &lt;a href=&#34;https://analytics.google.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Google Analytics&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://disqus.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Disqus&lt;/a&gt; comments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Responsive and mobile friendly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simple and refreshing one page design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multilingual and easy to customize&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;color-themes&#34;&gt;Color Themes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Academic is available in different color themes and font themes.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;div class=&#34;gallery&#34;&gt;

  
  
  
  
    
    
    
    
    
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/etiennerey/gallery/theme-1950s.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;1950s&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/etiennerey/gallery/theme-1950s_huaf5482f8cea0c5a703a328640e3b7509_21614_0x190_resize_box_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/etiennerey/gallery/theme-apogee.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Apogee&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/etiennerey/gallery/theme-apogee_hu4b45d99db97150df01464c393bfd17d4_24119_0x190_resize_box_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/etiennerey/gallery/theme-coffee-playfair.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Coffee theme with Playfair font&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/etiennerey/gallery/theme-coffee-playfair_hu446a8f670cc5622adcc77b97ba95f6c5_22462_0x190_resize_box_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/etiennerey/gallery/theme-cupcake.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Cupcake&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/etiennerey/gallery/theme-cupcake_hueba8cfa8cfbc7543924fcbf387a99e92_23986_0x190_resize_box_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/etiennerey/gallery/theme-dark.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Dark&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/etiennerey/gallery/theme-dark_hu1e8601ecc47f58eada7743fdcd709d3d_21456_0x190_resize_box_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/etiennerey/gallery/theme-default.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Default&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/etiennerey/gallery/theme-default_huba6228b7bdf30e2f03f12ea91b2cba0d_21751_0x190_resize_box_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/etiennerey/gallery/theme-forest.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Forest&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/etiennerey/gallery/theme-forest_hu4f093a1c683134431456584193ea41ee_21797_0x190_resize_box_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/etiennerey/gallery/theme-ocean.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Ocean&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/etiennerey/gallery/theme-ocean_hu14831ccafc2219f30a7a096fa7617e01_21760_0x190_resize_box_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  

  
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ecosystem&#34;&gt;Ecosystem&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sourcethemes/academic-admin&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Academic Admin&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; An admin tool to import publications from BibTeX or import assets for an offline site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sourcethemes/academic-scripts&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Academic Scripts&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Scripts to help migrate content to new versions of Academic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;install&#34;&gt;Install&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can choose from one of the following four methods to install:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;one-click install using your web browser (recommended)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;install on your computer using Git with the Command Prompt/Terminal app&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;install on your computer by downloading the ZIP files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;install on your computer with RStudio&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;quick-install-using-your-web-browser&#34;&gt;Quick install using your web browser&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://app.netlify.com/start/deploy?repository=https://github.com/sourcethemes/academic-kickstart&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Install Academic with Netlify&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Netlify will provide you with a customizable URL to access your new site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On GitHub, go to your newly created &lt;code&gt;academic-kickstart&lt;/code&gt; repository and edit &lt;code&gt;config.toml&lt;/code&gt; to personalize your site. Shortly after saving the file, your site will automatically update&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Quick Start Guide&lt;/a&gt; to learn how to add Markdown content. For inspiration, refer to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/tree/master/exampleSite&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Markdown content&lt;/a&gt; which powers the &lt;a href=&#34;https://academic-demo.netlify.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Demo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;install-with-git&#34;&gt;Install with Git&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prerequisites:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://git-scm.com/downloads&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Download and install Git&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/getting-started/installing/#quick-install&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Download and install Hugo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sourcethemes/academic-kickstart#fork-destination-box&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Fork&lt;/a&gt; the &lt;em&gt;Academic Kickstart&lt;/em&gt; repository and clone your fork with Git:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git clone https://github.com/sourcethemes/academic-kickstart.git My_Website
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note that if you forked Academic Kickstart, the above command should be edited to clone your fork, i.e. replace &lt;code&gt;sourcethemes&lt;/code&gt; with your GitHub username.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Initialize the theme:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd My_Website
git submodule update --init --recursive
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;install-with-zip&#34;&gt;Install with ZIP&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sourcethemes/academic-kickstart/archive/master.zip&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt; and extract &lt;em&gt;Academic Kickstart&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/archive/master.zip&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt; and extract the &lt;em&gt;Academic theme&lt;/em&gt; to the &lt;code&gt;themes/academic/&lt;/code&gt; folder from the above step&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;install-with-rstudio&#34;&gt;Install with RStudio&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/install/#install-with-rstudio&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;View the guide to installing Academic with RStudio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;quick-start&#34;&gt;Quick start&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you installed on your computer, view your new website by running the following command:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;hugo server
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now visit &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;localhost:1313&lt;/a&gt; and your new Academic powered website will appear. Otherwise, if using Netlify, they will provide you with your URL.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Quick Start Guide&lt;/a&gt; to learn how to add Markdown content, customize your site, and deploy it. For inspiration, refer to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/tree/master/exampleSite&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Markdown content&lt;/a&gt; which powers the &lt;a href=&#34;https://academic-demo.netlify.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Demo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Build your site by running the &lt;code&gt;hugo&lt;/code&gt; command. Then &lt;a href=&#34;https://georgecushen.com/create-your-website-with-hugo/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;host it for free using Github Pages&lt;/a&gt; or Netlify (refer to the first installation method). Alternatively, copy the generated &lt;code&gt;public/&lt;/code&gt; directory (by FTP, Rsync, etc.) to your production web server (such as a university&amp;rsquo;s hosting service).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;updating&#34;&gt;Updating&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel free to &lt;em&gt;star&lt;/em&gt; the project on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; to help keep track of updates and check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/updates&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;release notes&lt;/a&gt; prior to updating your site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before updating the framework, it is recommended to make a backup of your entire website directory (or at least your &lt;code&gt;themes/academic&lt;/code&gt; directory) and record your current version number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By default, Academic is installed as a Git submodule which can be updated by running the following command:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;git submodule update --remote --merge
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/update/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Check out the update guide&lt;/a&gt; for full instructions and alternative methods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;feedback-contributing&#34;&gt;Feedback &amp;amp; Contributing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/issues&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;issue tracker&lt;/a&gt; to let me know about any bugs or feature requests, or alternatively make a pull request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For support, head over to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://discuss.gohugo.io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hugo discussion forum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;license&#34;&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Copyright 2016-present &lt;a href=&#34;https://georgecushen.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;George Cushen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Released under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/blob/master/LICENSE.md&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;MIT&lt;/a&gt; license.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A dynamic model for decoding direction and orientation in macaque primary visual cortex</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/taouali-15-vss/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/taouali-15-vss/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian Modeling of Motion Perception using Dynamical Stochastic Textures</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/vacher-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/vacher-16/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compensation of oculomotor delays in the visual system&#39;s network.</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/perrinet-16-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/perrinet-16-networks/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
