<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Michael Breakspear | Novel visual computations</title>
    <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/authors/michael-breakspear/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://laurentperrinet.github.io/authors/michael-breakspear/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Michael Breakspear</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>This material is presented to ensure timely dissemination of scholarly and technical work. Copyright and all rights therein are retained by authors or by other copyright holders. All persons copying this information are expected to adhere to the terms and constraints invoked by each author&#39;s copyright. In most cases, these works may not be reposted without the explicit permission of the copyright holder. 
This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 3.0 Unported License Please note that multiple distribution, publication or commercial usage of copyrighted papers included in this website would require submission of a permission request addressed to the journal in which the paper appeared. </copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/img/hulk.png</url>
      <title>Michael Breakspear</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/authors/michael-breakspear/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perceptions as Hypotheses: Saccades as Experiments</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/friston-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/friston-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;friston-12.png&#34; alt=&#34;header&#34;&gt;













&lt;figure&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://www.frontiersin.org/files/Articles/21922/fpsyg-03-00151-r4/image_m/fpsyg-03-00151-g001.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;This schematic shows the dependencies among various quantities that are assumed when modeling the exchanges of a self organizing system like the brain with the environment. The top panel describes the states of the environment and the system or agent in terms of a probabilistic dependency graph, where connections denote directed dependencies. The quantities are described within the nodes of this graph with exemplar forms for their dependencies on other variables (see main text). Here, hidden and internal states are separated by action and sensory states. Both action and internal states encoding a conditional density minimize free energy, while internal states encoding prior beliefs maximize salience. Both free energy and salience are defined in terms of a generative model that is shown as fictive dependency graph in the lower panel. Note that the variables in the real world and the form of their dynamics are different from that assumed by the generative model; this is why external states are in bold. Furthermore, note that action is a state in the model of the brain but is replaced by hidden controls in the brain’s model of its world. This means that the agent is not aware of action but has beliefs about hidden causes in the world that action can fulfill through minimizing free energy. These beliefs correspond to prior expectations that sensory states will be sampled in a way that optimizes conditional confidence or salience.&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.frontiersin.org/files/Articles/21922/fpsyg-03-00151-r4/image_m/fpsyg-03-00151-g001.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; &gt;&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;This schematic shows the dependencies among various quantities that are assumed when modeling the exchanges of a self organizing system like the brain with the environment.&lt;/strong&gt; The top panel describes the states of the environment and the system or agent in terms of a probabilistic dependency graph, where connections denote directed dependencies. The quantities are described within the nodes of this graph with exemplar forms for their dependencies on other variables (see main text). Here, hidden and internal states are separated by action and sensory states. Both action and internal states encoding a conditional density minimize free energy, while internal states encoding prior beliefs maximize salience. Both free energy and salience are defined in terms of a generative model that is shown as fictive dependency graph in the lower panel. Note that the variables in the real world and the form of their dynamics are different from that assumed by the generative model; this is why external states are in bold. Furthermore, note that action is a state in the model of the brain but is replaced by hidden controls in the brain’s model of its world. This means that the agent is not aware of action but has beliefs about hidden causes in the world that action can fulfill through minimizing free energy. These beliefs correspond to prior expectations that sensory states will be sampled in a way that optimizes conditional confidence or salience.
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
