<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>grant on Novel computational paradigms for vision</title>
    <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/tags/grant/</link>
    <description>Recent content in grant on Novel computational paradigms for vision</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This material is presented to ensure timely dissemination of scholarly and technical work. Copyright and all rights therein are retained by authors or by other copyright holders. All persons copying this information are expected to adhere to the terms and constraints invoked by each author&#39;s copyright. In most cases, these works may not be reposted without the explicit permission of the copyright holder.
&lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Creative Commons License&#34; style=&#34;border-width:0&#34; src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/3.0/88x31.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This work is licensed under a &lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 3.0 Unported License&lt;/a&gt;
Please note that multiple distribution, publication or commercial usage of copyrighted papers included in this website would require submission of a permission request addressed to the journal in which the paper appeared.
</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://laurentperrinet.github.io/tags/grant/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>DOC2AMU (2016--2019)</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/project/doc-2-amu/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/project/doc-2-amu/</guid>
      <description>DOC2AMU is co-funded by the prestigious Marie Skłodowska-Curie COFUND action within the H2020 Research and Innovation programme of the European Union and by the Regional Council of Provence-Alpes-Côte d’Azur, with a contribution from A*MIDEX Foundation.
Within this programme, the PhD fellows will sign a three-year work contract with one of the 12 Doctoral Schools of AMU. Numerous advantages
These PhD fellowships are remunerated above that of a standard French PhD contract with a gross monthly salary of 2600 € and a gross monthly mobility allowance of 300 €, which after standard deductions will amount to a net salary of approximately 1625€/month (net amount may vary slightly).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhD ICN (2017 / 2021)</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/project/phd-icn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/project/phd-icn/</guid>
      <description>Description
The Ph.D. program in Integrative and Clinical Neuroscience (Aix-Marseille University) is offering in 2017 three Ph.D. scholarships to Master students graduated from highly ranked international universities (outside France). We were awarded with one PhD position for Angelo Franciosini at the &amp;quot;Institut de Neurosciences de la Timone&amp;quot; (team &amp;quot;Inference and Visual Behavior&amp;quot;), CNRS, Marseille (France) to study trajectories in natural images and the sensory processing of contours.  Funding
This project is funded by the Aix-Marseille Université, which was awarded the prestigious status of &amp;quot;Excellence Initiative&amp;quot; (A*MIDEX) by the French Government and considering interdisciplinary studies as one of its main axes of growth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CODDE (2008--2012)</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/project/codde/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/project/codde/</guid>
      <description>http://www.optimaldecisions.org/ The CODDE network studies the links between sensory input, brain activity and motor output. It does this by combining behavioural techniques, brain imaging, movement recording and computational modelling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FACETS (2006--2010)</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/project/brain-scales/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/project/brain-scales/</guid>
      <description>List of publications that were funded by the FACETS project (more info).
 also available on the FACET&amp;rsquo;s website  See also:
 The FACETS research project which ended on 31 August 2010.
 The FACETS-ITN Marie-Curie initital training network for graduate training continues until August 2013
 The BrainScaleS project builds on and extends the research done in FACETS. This 4 year project started on 1 January 2011</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FACETS (2006--2010)</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/project/facets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/project/facets/</guid>
      <description>List of publications that were funded by the FACETS project (more info).
 also available on the FACET&amp;rsquo;s website  See also:
 The FACETS research project which ended on 31 August 2010.
 The FACETS-ITN Marie-Curie initital training network for graduate training continues until August 2013
 The BrainScaleS project builds on and extends the research done in FACETS. This 4 year project started on 1 January 2011</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FACETS-ITN (2010--2013)</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/project/facets-itn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/project/facets-itn/</guid>
      <description>FACETS-ITN: From Neuroscience to neuro-inspired computing (2010&amp;ndash;2013) 
FACETS ITN project (EU funding, grant number 237955) is a &amp;lsquo;Marie-Curie Initial Training Network&amp;rsquo; involves 15 groups at European Research Universities, Research Centers and Industrial Partners in 6 countries. 22 Ph.D. Positions are funded in the FACETS-ITN project in the following scientific work areas: Neurobiology of Cells and Networks, Modelling of Neural Systems, Neuromorphic Hardware, Neuro-Electronic Interfaces, Computational Principles in Neural Architectures, Mechanisms of Learning and Plasticity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PACE-ITN (2015--2019)</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/project/pace-itn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/project/pace-itn/</guid>
      <description>The PACE ITN project involves over 50 researchers spread across 10 full and 5 associated partners, from academia and the private sector, established in 7 different European and Associated countries, the PACE network gathers a broad range of expertise from experimental psychology, cognitive neurosciences, brain imaging, technology and clinical sciences.
The PACE Project has received funding from the European Union’s Horizon 2020 research and innovation programme under the Marie Sklodowska-Curie grant agreement No 642961</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>