<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>doc-2-amu on Novel visual computations</title>
    <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/tags/doc-2-amu/</link>
    <description>Recent content in doc-2-amu on Novel visual computations</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This material is presented to ensure timely dissemination of scholarly and technical work. Copyright and all rights therein are retained by authors or by other copyright holders. All persons copying this information are expected to adhere to the terms and constraints invoked by each author&#39;s copyright. In most cases, these works may not be reposted without the explicit permission of the copyright holder.
&lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Creative Commons License&#34; style=&#34;border-width:0&#34; src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/3.0/88x31.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This work is licensed under a &lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 3.0 Unported License&lt;/a&gt;
Please note that multiple distribution, publication or commercial usage of copyrighted papers included in this website would require submission of a permission request addressed to the journal in which the paper appeared.
</copyright>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://laurentperrinet.github.io/tags/doc-2-amu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/authors/victor-boutin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/authors/victor-boutin/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;controlling-an-aerial-robot-by-human-semaphore-gestures-using-a-bio-inspired-neural-network-phd-12-2016-02-2020&#34;&gt;Controlling an aerial robot by human semaphore gestures using a bio-inspired neural network (PhD, &lt;sup&gt;12&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2016&lt;/sub&gt;-02/2020)&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Venue: Aix-Marseille University &lt;a href=&#34;https://doc2amu.univ-amu.fr/fr/victor-boutin-doctorant-promotion-2016&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;DOC2AMU&lt;/a&gt; is an innovative H2020-MSCA-COFUND&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keywords: Aerial Robots, Vision, Neural Networks, Bio-Inspired Computer Vision, Gaze orientation, learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thesis director: Dr. Laurent PERRINET, Director&amp;rsquo;s research unit: Institut de Neurosciences de la Timone (INT)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thesis co-supervisition: Dr. Franck RUFFIER Co-director&amp;rsquo;s research unit: Institut des Sciences du Mouvement (ISM)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;description-of-the-phd-thesis-project&#34;&gt;Description of the PHD thesis project&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Robotics is a rapidly evolving technology that allows for fast, low-risk
and low-cost tasks with a worldwide market of over 80 billion dollars
over the next few years. In particular, aerial robots, also known as
drones, provide a breakthrough to easily image and access all sorts of
terrains and situations and are useful for instance in surveillance and
forensics, emergency industrial inspection or a search and rescue
operation. A major difficulty for their global acceptance is the
difficulty for controlling their flight and interacting with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indeed, aerial robots are generally operated using a (central) ground
station which is not compatible with the time pressure required by
emergency conditions, for instance when
rescuing a person out of reach with the ground station. This PhD project
aims at concealing such obstacles and construct an aerial robot which is
able to be autonomously and interactively controlled by simple human
gestures, for instance that of a rescuer. The main scientific challenges
are (i) to embed in the aerial robot all the electronics for the visual
system from the retina to the control signals to the propellers, (ii) to
very quickly recognize a variety of simple gestures on-board using a
neuromimetic architecture and (iii) to make the robot react in real time
to these gestures. As such, this project is inter-disciplinary by
positively combining advanced algorithms from event-based bio-inspired
computer vision and the latest technology in aerial robots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;R. Benosman , S.-H. Leng , C. Clercq , C. Bartolozzi &amp;amp; M. Srinivasan (2012) “Asynchronous frameless event-based optical flow”, Neural Networks - Elsevier&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;S.-C. Liu &amp;amp; T. Delbruck (2010) “Neuromorphic sensory systems”, Current opinion in neurobiology - Elsevier&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;J. Nagi, A. Giusti, G. A. Di Caro, L. M. Gambardella (2014) “HRI in the Sky, Controlling UAVs using Face Poses and Hand Gestures”, HRI&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;3i-dimensions-and-other-aspects-of-the-project&#34;&gt;3I dimensions and other aspects of the project&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The present PhD proposal is at the crossroad between various
 disciplines. It first concerns biology and neuroscience because its
 event-based approach is strongly inspired from the neuronal network
 observed in animals such as insects to primates and used for navigation,
 obstacle avoidance, and sensori-motor control. It is also covering
 electronics, aerial robotics and signal processing as the main project
 achievement is to create a working spike-based electronic architecture
 able to recognize body movement, and to use it to control the robot.
 Such an oucome will have beneficial outcomes with respects to the SRI-S3
 regional strategy, in particular with respect to “risks, security and
 safety”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project is a partnership between two different doctoral schools
 based in Marseille: the EDSMH at ISM for the robotic part, and the EDSVS
 at INT concerning visual processing and spike-based processing methods.
 This partnership will provide the ESR with the best resources to achieve
 his goals. In particular, the ISM owns a brand new flying arena (funded
 by Robotex project, www.marseilles-flying-arena.eu) equipped with
 high-tech motion capture tools (Vicon) and the INT has a entire
 technological platform dedicated for high-performance computing and
 measurement tool prototyping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Combining neuroscience and robotics to design novel electronic
 architectures is an innovative and a valuable approach in Robotics. The
 doctoral student selected for this project will acquire experience in
 bio-inspired hardware architectures, which is going to be valuable in
 his career as there is a need to adapt actual electronic architecture to
 for instance spike-based visual processing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
