<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Events on Novel visual computations</title>
    <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Events on Novel visual computations</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This material is presented to ensure timely dissemination of scholarly and technical work. Copyright and all rights therein are retained by authors or by other copyright holders. All persons copying this information are expected to adhere to the terms and constraints invoked by each author&#39;s copyright. In most cases, these works may not be reposted without the explicit permission of the copyright holder.
&lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Creative Commons License&#34; style=&#34;border-width:0&#34; src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/3.0/88x31.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This work is licensed under a &lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 3.0 Unported License&lt;/a&gt;
Please note that multiple distribution, publication or commercial usage of copyrighted papers included in this website would require submission of a permission request addressed to the journal in which the paper appeared.
</copyright>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Illusions et hallucinations visuelles : une porte sur la perception</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/2019-06-06-theconversation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/2019-06-06-theconversation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurentperrinet.github.io/2019-05_illusions-visuelles/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://laurentperrinet.github.io/2019-05_illusions-visuelles/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Les objectifs sont : – mieux comprendre la fonction de la perception visuelle en explorant certaines limites ; – mieux comprendre l’importance de l’aspect dynamique de la perception ; – mieux comprendre le rôle de l’action dans la perception.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical neuroscience Symposium on Active Inference at NeuroFrance 2019</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/2019-05-23-neurofrance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/2019-05-23-neurofrance/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;active-inference-bridging-theoretical-and-experimental-neurosciences-inference-active-un-pont-entre-neurosciences-théoriques-et-expérimentales&#34;&gt;Active Inference: Bridging theoretical and experimental neurosciences. / Inference Active: Un pont entre neurosciences théoriques et expérimentales.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.neurosciences.asso.fr/V2/colloques/SN19/index_en.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://neuro-marseille.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/capture-decran-2018-07-06-a-190423.png&#34; alt=&#34;Site NeuroFrance&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SYMPOSIUM S17&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When: 23.05.2019 11:00-13:00h&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When: Endoume 1+2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;s17-1-https-www-professionalabstracts-com-nf2019-iplanner-presentation-1397-active-inference-and-brain-computer-interfaces-inférence-active-et-interfaces-cerveau-machine&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.professionalabstracts.com/nf2019/iplanner/#/presentation/1397&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;S17.1&lt;/a&gt;  Active inference and Brain-Computer Interfaces / Inférence active et interfaces cerveau-machine&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mattout J. (Lyon, France), Mladenovic J. (Lyon, France), Frey J. (Bordeaux, France)3, Joffily M. (Lyon, France), Maby E. (Lyon, France), Lotte F. (Lyon, France)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brain-Computer Interfaces (BCIs) devices bypass natural pathways to connect the brain with a machine, directly. They may rely on invasive or non-invasive measures of brain activity and applications cover a large domain, mostly but not restricted to clinical ones. A major objective is to restore communication and autonomy in heavily motor impaired patients.
However, no BCI has made its way to a routinely used clinical application yet. One lead for improvement is to endow the machine with learning abilities so that it can optimize its decisions and adapt to changes in the user signals over time1. Several approaches have been proposed but a generic framework is still lacking to foster the development of efficient adaptive BCIs2.
Initially proposed to model perception, learning and action by the brain, the Active Inference (AI) framework offers great promises in that aim3. It rests on an explicit generative model of the environment. In BCI, from the machine&amp;rsquo;s point of view, brain signals play the role of sensory inputs on which the machine&amp;rsquo;s perception of mental states will be based. Furthermore, the machine builds up decisions and trades between different actions such as: go on observing, deciding to decide, correcting its previous action or moving on.
In this talk, I will present an instantiation of AI in the context of the EEG-based P300-speller BCI for communication, showing it can flexibly combine complementary adaptive features pertaining to both perception and action, and yield significant improvements as shown on realistic simulations. We will discuss perspectives to further extend the current model and performance as well as the challenges ahead to implement this framework online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mattout, J. Brain-Computer Interfaces: A Neuroscience Paradigm of Social Interaction? A Matter of Perspective. Frontiers in Human Neuroscience 6, (2012).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mladenovic, J., Mattout, J. &amp;amp; Lotte, F. A Generic Framework for Adaptive EEG-Based BCI Training and Operation. in Brain-computer interfaces handbook: technological and theoretical advances (eds. Nam, C. S., Nijholt, A. &amp;amp; Lotte, F.) Chapter 31 (Taylor &amp;amp; Francis, CRC Press, 2018).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Friston, K., Mattout, J. &amp;amp; Kilner, J. Action understanding and active inference. Biological Cybernetics 104, 137-160 (2011).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;s17-2-https-www-professionalabstracts-com-nf2019-iplanner-presentation-1398-comparing-active-inference-and-reinforcement-learning-models-of-a-go-nogo-task-and-their-relationships-to-striatal-dopamine-2-receptors-assessed-using-pet-comparaison-des-modèles-d-inférence-active-et-d-apprentissage-par-renforcement-dans-une-tâche-go-nogo-relation-avec-les-récepteurs-dopaminergiques-d2-striataux-évalués-par-tep&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.professionalabstracts.com/nf2019/iplanner/#/presentation/1398&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;S17.2&lt;/a&gt;  Comparing active inference and reinforcement learning models of a Go NoGo task and their relationships to striatal dopamine 2 receptors assessed using PET / Comparaison des modèles d&amp;rsquo;inférence active et d&amp;rsquo;apprentissage par renforcement dans une tâche Go / NoGo : relation avec les récepteurs dopaminergiques D2 striataux évalués par TEP&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;R. Adams (London)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.professionalabstracts.com/nf2019/iplanner/#/presentation/1398&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://www.professionalabstracts.com/nf2019/iplanner/#/presentation/1398&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adaptive behaviour includes the ability to choose actions that result in advantageous outcomes. It is key to survival and a fundamental function of nervous systems. Active inference (AI) and reinforcement learning (RL) are two influential models of how the brain might achieve this. A key AI parameter is the precision of beliefs about policies. Precision controls the stochasticity of action selection - similar to decision temperature in RL - and is thought to be encoded by striatal dopamine. 75 healthy subjects performed a &amp;lsquo;go/no-go&amp;rsquo; task, and we measured striatal dopamine &lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; receptor (D2/3R) availability in a subset of 25 using [11C]-(+)-PHNO positron emission tomography. In behavioural model comparison, RL performed best across the whole group but AI performed best in accurate subjects. D2/3R availability in the limbic striatum correlated with AI policy precision and also with RL irreducible decision &amp;lsquo;noise&amp;rsquo;. Limbic striatal D2/3R availability also correlated with AI Pavlovian prior beliefs - i.e. the respective probabilities of making or withholding actions in rewarding or loss-avoiding contexts - and the RL learning rate. These findings are consistent with the notion that occupancy of inhibitory striatal D2/3Rs controls the variability of action selection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;s17-3-https-www-professionalabstracts-com-nf2019-iplanner-presentation-1399-principles-and-psychophysics-of-active-inference-in-anticipating-a-dynamic-switching-probabilistic-bias-principes-et-psychophysique-de-l-inférence-active-dans-l-estimation-d-un-biais-dynamique-et-volatile-de-probabilité&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.professionalabstracts.com/nf2019/iplanner/#/presentation/1399&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;S17.3&lt;/a&gt;  Principles and psychophysics of active inference in anticipating a dynamic, switching probabilistic bias / Principes et psychophysique de l&amp;rsquo;inférence active dans l´estimation d&amp;rsquo;un biais dynamique et volatile de probabilité&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;L. Perrinet (Marseille)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;see more info on this &lt;a href=&#34;https://laurentperrinet.github.io/talk/2019-05-23-neurofrance/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;talk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;s17-4-https-www-professionalabstracts-com-nf2019-iplanner-presentation-1400-is-laziness-contagious-a-computational-approach-to-attitude-alignment-la-fainéantise-est-elle-contagieuse-une-approche-computationnelle-de-l-alignement-des-attitudes&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.professionalabstracts.com/nf2019/iplanner/#/presentation/1400&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;S17.4&lt;/a&gt;  Is laziness contagious? A computational approach to attitude alignment / La fainéantise est-elle contagieuse? Une approche computationnelle de l´alignement des attitudes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;J. Daunizeau (Paris)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do people learn from observing others´ attitudes, such as prudence, impatience or laziness? Rather than viewing these attitudes as examples of subjective and biologically entrenched personality traits, we assume that they derive from uncertain (and mostly implicit) beliefs about how to best weigh risks, delays and efforts in ensuing cost-benefit trade-offs. In this view, it is adaptive to update one´s belief after having observed others´ attitude, which provides valuable information regarding how to best behave in related difficult decision contexts. This is the starting point of our bayesian model of attitude alignment, which we derive in the light of recent neuroimaging findings. First, we disclose a few non-trivial predictions from this model. Second, we validate these predictions experimentally by profiling people´s prudence, impatience and laziness both before and after guessing a series of cost-benefit arbitrages performed by calibrated artificial agents (which are impersonating human individuals). Third, we extend these findings and assess attitude alignment in autistic individuals. Finally, we discuss the relevance and implications of this work, with a particular emphasis on the assessment of biases of social cognition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;s17-5-https-www-professionalabstracts-com-nf2019-iplanner-presentation-223-generative-bayesian-modeling-for-causal-inference-between-neural-activity-and-behavior-in-drosophila-larva&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.professionalabstracts.com/nf2019/iplanner/#/presentation/223&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;S17.5&lt;/a&gt;   Generative Bayesian modeling for causal inference between neural activity and behavior in Drosophila larva&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;C. Barre (Paris) (TBC)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A fundamental property of the central nervous system is its ability to select appropriate behavioral patterns or sequences of behavioral patterns in response to sensory cues, but what are the biological mechanisms underlying decision making? The Drosophila larva is an ideal animal model for reverse-engineering the neural processes underlying behavior. The full connectome of the larva brain has been imaged at the individual-synapse level using electron microscopy.
The host of genetic techniques available for Drosophila allows us to optogenetically manipulate over 1,500 of its roughly 12,000 neurons individually in freely behaving larvae.
This enables us to establish causal relationships between neural activity, and behavior at the fundamental level of individual neurons and neural connections.
We have access to video record of the individual behavior of ~3,000,000 larvae. We have identified 6 stereotypical behavioral patterns using a combination of supervised and unsupervised machine learning. The behavioral identified for the larva: crawl, turn, stop, crawl backward, hunch (retract the head), and roll (lateral slide). Each realization of a behavioral pattern is characterized by a different duration, amplitude, and velocity.
Here we present a generative model that extracts the behavior of wildtype larvae using Bayesian inference, and interprets behavioral changes following neuron activation or inactivation from large-scale experimental screens. Fig. shows the average behavior of 10,000 larvae over time in a screen where a single neuron is activated at t=30s. A clear change in behavior is seen following activation is seen which is well captured by the model, illustrating its accuracy.
The generative model enables us to robustly detect behavioral modifications as significant deviations of the patterns in the larvae&amp;rsquo;s sequence of activities from their equilibrium behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;neurofrance-marseille-capitale-des-neurosciences&#34;&gt;NeuroFrance: Marseille, capitale des neurosciences&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Du  22 au 24 mai 2019 au Palais des congrès de Marseille (Parc Chanot), près de 1300 chercheurs, cliniciens et étudiants venus du monde entier partageront leurs travaux lors de NeuroFrance 2019, colloque international organisé par la Société des Neurosciences.Au total, 8 conférences plénières, 42 symposiums, 6 sessions spécialisées, 525 communications affichées, ainsi qu’une exposition avec 42 entreprises et sociétés de biotechnologies, feront de ce colloque un moment exceptionnel pour mettre en lumière les avancées majeures scientifiques et technologiques sur le fonctionnement du cerveau. Vous pourrez aussi découvrir le &amp;ldquo;Neurovillage&amp;rdquo; qui permettra de vous immerger au cœur des innovations neuroscientifiques marseillaises, ainsi que  l’exposition  « L’Art en tête », composée de cinq œuvres originales créées par des artistes et des scientifiques. Plusieurs événements seront également proposés autour du colloque pour le grand public comme pour les chercheurs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Academic: the website designer for Hugo</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/etiennerey/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/etiennerey/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Academic&lt;/strong&gt; makes it easy to create a beautiful website for free using Markdown. Customize anything on your site with widgets, themes, and language packs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow our easy &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/install/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;step by step guide&lt;/a&gt; to learn how to build your own free website with Academic. &lt;a href=&#34;https://academic-demo.netlify.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Check out the personal demo&lt;/a&gt; or the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;business demo&lt;/a&gt; of what you&amp;rsquo;ll get in less than 10 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;View the documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://discuss.gohugo.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ask a question&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/issues&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Request a feature or report a bug&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updating? View the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/update/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Update Guide&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/updates/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Release Notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support development of Academic:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://paypal.me/cushen&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Donate a coffee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.patreon.com/cushen&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Become a backer on Patreon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.redbubble.com/people/neutreno/works/34387919-academic&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Decorate your laptop or journal with an Academic sticker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://academic.threadless.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wear the T-shirt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/master/academic.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Key features:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easily manage various content including homepage, blog posts, publications, talks, and projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extensible via &lt;strong&gt;color themes&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;widgets/plugins&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write in &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Markdown&lt;/a&gt; for easy formatting and code highlighting, with &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikibooks.org/wiki/LaTeX/Mathematics&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;LaTeX&lt;/a&gt; for mathematical expressions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Social/academic network linking, &lt;a href=&#34;https://analytics.google.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Google Analytics&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://disqus.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Disqus&lt;/a&gt; comments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Responsive and mobile friendly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simple and refreshing one page design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multilingual and easy to customize&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;color-themes&#34;&gt;Color Themes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Academic is available in different color themes and font themes.&lt;/p&gt;









  
  


&lt;div class=&#34;gallery&#34;&gt;

  
  
  
  
    
    
    
    
    
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/etiennerey/gallery/theme-1950s.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;1950s&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/etiennerey/gallery/theme-1950s_huaf5482f8cea0c5a703a328640e3b7509_21614_0x190_resize_lanczos_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/etiennerey/gallery/theme-apogee.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Apogee&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/etiennerey/gallery/theme-apogee_hu4b45d99db97150df01464c393bfd17d4_24119_0x190_resize_lanczos_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/etiennerey/gallery/theme-coffee-playfair.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Coffee theme with Playfair font&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/etiennerey/gallery/theme-coffee-playfair_hu446a8f670cc5622adcc77b97ba95f6c5_22462_0x190_resize_lanczos_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/etiennerey/gallery/theme-cupcake.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Cupcake&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/etiennerey/gallery/theme-cupcake_hueba8cfa8cfbc7543924fcbf387a99e92_23986_0x190_resize_lanczos_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/etiennerey/gallery/theme-dark.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Dark&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/etiennerey/gallery/theme-dark_hu1e8601ecc47f58eada7743fdcd709d3d_21456_0x190_resize_lanczos_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/etiennerey/gallery/theme-default.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Default&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/etiennerey/gallery/theme-default_huba6228b7bdf30e2f03f12ea91b2cba0d_21751_0x190_resize_lanczos_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/etiennerey/gallery/theme-forest.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Forest&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/etiennerey/gallery/theme-forest_hu4f093a1c683134431456584193ea41ee_21797_0x190_resize_lanczos_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/etiennerey/gallery/theme-ocean.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Ocean&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/etiennerey/gallery/theme-ocean_hu14831ccafc2219f30a7a096fa7617e01_21760_0x190_resize_lanczos_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  

  
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ecosystem&#34;&gt;Ecosystem&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sourcethemes/academic-admin&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Academic Admin&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; An admin tool to import publications from BibTeX or import assets for an offline site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sourcethemes/academic-scripts&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Academic Scripts&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Scripts to help migrate content to new versions of Academic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;install&#34;&gt;Install&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can choose from one of the following four methods to install:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;one-click install using your web browser (recommended)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;install on your computer using Git with the Command Prompt/Terminal app&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;install on your computer by downloading the ZIP files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;install on your computer with RStudio&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;quick-install-using-your-web-browser&#34;&gt;Quick install using your web browser&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://app.netlify.com/start/deploy?repository=https://github.com/sourcethemes/academic-kickstart&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Install Academic with Netlify&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Netlify will provide you with a customizable URL to access your new site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On GitHub, go to your newly created &lt;code&gt;academic-kickstart&lt;/code&gt; repository and edit &lt;code&gt;config.toml&lt;/code&gt; to personalize your site. Shortly after saving the file, your site will automatically update&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Quick Start Guide&lt;/a&gt; to learn how to add Markdown content. For inspiration, refer to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/tree/master/exampleSite&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Markdown content&lt;/a&gt; which powers the &lt;a href=&#34;https://academic-demo.netlify.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Demo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;install-with-git&#34;&gt;Install with Git&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prerequisites:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://git-scm.com/downloads&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Download and install Git&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/getting-started/installing/#quick-install&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Download and install Hugo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sourcethemes/academic-kickstart#fork-destination-box&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Fork&lt;/a&gt; the &lt;em&gt;Academic Kickstart&lt;/em&gt; repository and clone your fork with Git:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git clone https://github.com/sourcethemes/academic-kickstart.git My_Website
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note that if you forked Academic Kickstart, the above command should be edited to clone your fork, i.e. replace &lt;code&gt;sourcethemes&lt;/code&gt; with your GitHub username.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Initialize the theme:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd My_Website
git submodule update --init --recursive
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;install-with-zip&#34;&gt;Install with ZIP&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sourcethemes/academic-kickstart/archive/master.zip&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt; and extract &lt;em&gt;Academic Kickstart&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/archive/master.zip&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt; and extract the &lt;em&gt;Academic theme&lt;/em&gt; to the &lt;code&gt;themes/academic/&lt;/code&gt; folder from the above step&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;install-with-rstudio&#34;&gt;Install with RStudio&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/install/#install-with-rstudio&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;View the guide to installing Academic with RStudio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;quick-start&#34;&gt;Quick start&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you installed on your computer, view your new website by running the following command:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;hugo server
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now visit &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;localhost:1313&lt;/a&gt; and your new Academic powered website will appear. Otherwise, if using Netlify, they will provide you with your URL.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Quick Start Guide&lt;/a&gt; to learn how to add Markdown content, customize your site, and deploy it. For inspiration, refer to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/tree/master/exampleSite&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Markdown content&lt;/a&gt; which powers the &lt;a href=&#34;https://academic-demo.netlify.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Demo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Build your site by running the &lt;code&gt;hugo&lt;/code&gt; command. Then &lt;a href=&#34;https://georgecushen.com/create-your-website-with-hugo/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;host it for free using Github Pages&lt;/a&gt; or Netlify (refer to the first installation method). Alternatively, copy the generated &lt;code&gt;public/&lt;/code&gt; directory (by FTP, Rsync, etc.) to your production web server (such as a university&amp;rsquo;s hosting service).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;updating&#34;&gt;Updating&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel free to &lt;em&gt;star&lt;/em&gt; the project on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; to help keep track of updates and check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/updates&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;release notes&lt;/a&gt; prior to updating your site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before updating the framework, it is recommended to make a backup of your entire website directory (or at least your &lt;code&gt;themes/academic&lt;/code&gt; directory) and record your current version number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By default, Academic is installed as a Git submodule which can be updated by running the following command:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;git submodule update --remote --merge
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/update/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Check out the update guide&lt;/a&gt; for full instructions and alternative methods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;feedback-contributing&#34;&gt;Feedback &amp;amp; Contributing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/issues&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;issue tracker&lt;/a&gt; to let me know about any bugs or feature requests, or alternatively make a pull request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For support, head over to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://discuss.gohugo.io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hugo discussion forum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;license&#34;&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Copyright 2016-present &lt;a href=&#34;https://georgecushen.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;George Cushen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Released under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/blob/master/LICENSE.md&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;MIT&lt;/a&gt; license.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proverbes Et Citations</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/proverbes-et-citations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/proverbes-et-citations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I do know what time is,&amp;rdquo; Tubby declared. He paused. &amp;ldquo;Time,&amp;rdquo; he added slowly &amp;ndash; &amp;ldquo;time is what keeps everything from happening at once. I know that&amp;ndash;I seen it in print too.&amp;rdquo; (Ray Cummings)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You don’t see it because it’s there, it’s there because you see it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ni rire, ni pleurer, ni haïr, mais comprendre&amp;rdquo; (Baruch Spinoza)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;For years there has been a theory that millions of monkeys typing at random on millions of typewriters would reproduce the entire works of Shakespeare. The Internet has proven this theory to be untrue.&amp;rdquo; (???, ???)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Je me suis endormie, ce matin/en pensant/sur tes lèvres.&amp;rdquo;  (Anonyme, sur les murs, Marseille, 2017)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If you can look into the seeds of time, And say which grain will grow and which will not; Speak&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; (Shakespeare, Macbeth, Act I, Scene 3)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Here, too, the honorable finds its due, and there are tears for passing things; here, too, things mortal touch the mind.&amp;rdquo; (Virgil, Aeneid, 29-19 BC)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Man&amp;rsquo;s maturity is to have regained the seriousness that he had as a child at play.&amp;rdquo; (Friedrich Nietzsche)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There are 10 types of people in the world. Those who understand binary, those who don&amp;rsquo;t, those who weren&amp;rsquo;t expecting a base 8 joke, and 5 other types of people.&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;http://unix.stackexchange.com/questions/178162/why-does-bash-think-016-1-15&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;John Story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ce qui fut se refait; tout coule comme une eau / Et rien dessous le Ciel ne se voit de nouveau/ Mais la forme se change en une autre nouvelle/ Et ce changement-là. Vivre au monde s&amp;rsquo;appelle&amp;rdquo; - Ronsard, Hymnes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hanlon&amp;rsquo;s Razor: Never attribute to malice what is adequately explained by stupidity.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Essentially, all models are wrong, but some are useful.&amp;rdquo; &amp;mdash; Box, George E. P.; Norman R. Draper (1987). Empirical Model-Building and Response Surfaces, p. 424, Wiley. ISBN 0471810339&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Computers were around for 50 years before we figured out how to create the internet for example.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;In sum, the physicist can never subject an isolated hypothesis to experimental test, but only a whole group of hypotheses; when the experiment is in disagreement with his predictions, what he learns is that at least one of the hypotheses constituting this group is unacceptable and ought to be modified; but the experiment does not designate which one should be changed.&amp;rdquo; (P. Duhem, The Aim and Structure of Physical Theory, 1914)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Un bon maître a ce souci constant : enseigner à se passer de lui.&amp;rdquo; - André Gide&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Truth in science can be defined as the working hypothesis best suited to open the way to the next better one.”(Konrad Lorenz)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;“all motion is illusion” (Zeno of Elea, 490 BC )&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Be humble for you are made of dung. Be noble for you are made of stars.&amp;rdquo; (Serbian proverb)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;voir des objets ne consiste pas à en extraire des traits visuels, mais à guider visuellement l&amp;rsquo;action dirigée vers eux.&amp;rdquo;  (Francisco Varela in &amp;ldquo;L&amp;rsquo;inscription corporelle de l&amp;rsquo;esprit&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;la mémoire n’est pas faite pour se rappeler du passé mais pour prédire le futur.&amp;rdquo; (&lt;a href=&#34;http://dpea-archi.philo.over-blog.com/article-interview-de-alain-berthoz-par-thierry-paquot-61601814.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Alain Berthoz&lt;/a&gt; , 2010)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the days when the Sussman was a novice, Minsky once came to him as he sat hacking at the PDP-6. &amp;ldquo;What are you doing?&amp;rdquo;, asked Minsky. &amp;ldquo;I am training a randomly wired neural net to play Tic-tac-toe&amp;rdquo;, Sussman replied. &amp;ldquo;Why is the net wired randomly?&amp;rdquo;, asked Minsky. &amp;ldquo;I do not want it to have any preconceptions of how to play&amp;rdquo;, Sussman said. Minsky then shut his eyes. &amp;ldquo;Why do you close your eyes?&amp;rdquo; Sussman asked his teacher. &amp;ldquo;So that the room will be empty.&amp;rdquo; At that moment, Sussman was enlightened.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter how beautiful your theory is, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter how smart you are. If it doesn&amp;rsquo;t agree with experiment, it&amp;rsquo;s wrong.&amp;rdquo; Richard P. Feynman&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Think of the image of the world in a convex mirror. &amp;hellip; A well-made convex mirror of moderate aperture represents the objects in front of it as apparently solid and in fixed positions behind its surface. But the images of the distant horizon and of the sun in the sky lie behind the mirror at a limited distance, equal to its focal length. Between these and the surface of the mirror are found the images of all the other objects before it, but the images are diminished and flattened in proportion to the distance of their objects from the mirror. &amp;hellip; Yet every straight line or plane in the outer world is represented by a straight line or plane in the image. The image of a man measuring with a rule a straight line from the mirror, would contract more and more the farther he went, but with his shrunken rule the man in the image would count out exactly the same results as in the outer world, all lines of sight in the mirror would be represented by straight lines of sight in the mirror. In short, I do not see how men in the mirror are to discover that their bodies are not rigid solids and their experiences good examples of the correctness of Euclidean axioms. But if they could look out upon our world as we look into theirs without overstepping the boundary, they must declare it to be a picture in a spherical mirror, and would speak of us just as we speak of them; and if two inhabitants of the different worlds could communicate with one another, neither, as far as I can see, would be able to convince the other that he had the true, the other the distorted, relation. Indeed I cannot see that such a question would have any meaning at all, so long as mechanical considerations are not mixed up with it.&amp;rdquo; — Hermann von Helmholtz In &amp;lsquo;On the Origin and Significance of Geometrical Axioms,&amp;rdquo; Popular Scientific Lectures&amp;lt; Second Series (1881), 57-59. In Robert  Moritz, Memorabilia Mathematica (1914), 357-358.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Whoever, in the pursuit of science, seeks after immediate practical utility, may generally rest assured that he will seek in vain.&amp;rdquo; — Hermann von Helmholtz, Edmund Atkinson (trans.), Popular Lectures on Scientific Subjects: First Series (1883), 29&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;« Au départ, l’art du puzzle semble un art bref, un art mince, tout entier contenu dans un maigre enseignement de la Gestalttheorie : l’objet visé — qu’il s’agisse d’un acte perceptif, d’un apprentissage, d’un système physiologique ou, dans le cas qui nous occupe, d’un puzzle en bois — n’est pas une somme d’éléments qu’il faudrait d’abord isoler et analyser, mais un ensemble, c’est à dire une forme, une structure : l’élément ne préexiste pas à l’ensemble, il n’est ni plus immédiat ni plus ancien, ce ne sont pas les éléments qui déterminent l’ensemble, mais l’ensemble qui détermine les éléments : la connaissance du tout et de ses lois, de l’ensemble et de sa structure, ne saurait être déduite de la connaissance séparée des parties qui le composent : cela veut dire qu’on peut regarder une pièce d’un puzzle pendant trois jours et croire tout savoir de sa configuration et de sa couleur sans avoir le moins du monde avancé : seule compte la possibilité de relier cette pièce à d’autres pièces et, en ce sens, il y a quelque chose de commun entre l’art du puzzle et l’art du go ; seules les pièces rassemblées prendront un caractère lisible, prendront un sens : considérée isolément, une pièce d’un puzzle ne veut rien dire ; elle est seulement question impossible, défi opaque ; mais à peine a-t-on réussi, au terme de plusieurs minutes d’essais et d’erreurs, ou en une demi-seconde prodigieusement inspirée, à la connecter à l’une de ses voisines, que la pièce disparaît, cesse d’exister en tant que pièce : l’intense difficulté qui a précédé ce rapprochement, et que le mot puzzle — énigme — désigne si bien en anglais, non seulement n’a plus de raison d’être, mais semble n’en avoir jamais eu, tant elle est devenue évidence : les deux pièces miraculeusement réunies n’en font plus qu’une, à son tour source d’erreur, d’hésitation, de désarroi et d’attente. » (PEREC Georges, La vie mode d’emploi, Éditions Hachette, 1978, pp. 235-236.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;there&amp;rsquo;s really a trend toward ATLs ( Acronyms of Three Letters).&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;In theory there is no difference between theory and practice. In practice there is.&amp;rdquo; Yogi Berra&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Les décorations, c&amp;rsquo;est comme les bombes, ça tombe toujours sur ceux qui ne les méritent pas&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lemonde.fr/societe/article/2010/03/22/proces-viguier-deux-hommes-en-colere_1322481_3224_1.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Me Dupond-Moretti&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Science is what we understand well enough to explain to a computer. Art is everything else we do.&amp;rdquo; D. Knuth, foreword to &amp;ldquo;A=B&amp;rdquo; (1995)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;les cons ça ose tout et c&amp;rsquo;est même à ça qu&amp;rsquo;on les reconnaît&amp;rdquo; (Audiard)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;All generalisations are dangerous, including this one.&amp;rdquo; (Alexandre Dumas)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Il vaut mieux mobiliser son intelligence sur des conneries que mobiliser sa connerie sur des choses intelligentes.&amp;rdquo; Jacques Rouxel&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Nothing in biology makes sense except in the light of evolution&amp;rdquo;. (Theodosius Dobzhansky, 1900–1975)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Copy from one, it’s plagiarism; copy from two, it’s research.&amp;rdquo; (Wilson Mizner)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;In the past the man has been first, in the future the system must be first.&amp;rdquo; (F. Taylor)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;L&amp;rsquo;autorité n&amp;rsquo;admet que deux rôles : le bourreau et la victime, transforme les gens en poupées qui ne connaissent plus que peur et haine, tandis que la culture plonge dans les abysses. L&amp;rsquo;autorité déforme ses enfants et change leur amour en un combat de coq&amp;hellip; L&amp;rsquo;effondrement de l&amp;rsquo;autorité aura des répercussions sur le bureau, l&amp;rsquo;église et l&amp;rsquo;école. Tout est lié. L&amp;rsquo;égalité et la liberté ne sont pas des luxes que l&amp;rsquo;on écarte impunément. Sans ceux-ci, l&amp;rsquo;ordre ne peut survivre longtemps sans se rapprocher de profondeurs inimaginables.&amp;rdquo; Alan Moore, &lt;a href=&#34;http://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/V_pour_Vendetta&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;V pour Vendetta&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;In a widely circulated joke [from the days of the first computer], a group of engineers assemble the most powerful computer that had ever been conceived and ask it the ultimate question: Is there a God? After several tense minutes of clicking and clacking and flashing of lights, a card pops out which reads: There is &amp;ldquo;now&amp;rdquo;.&amp;rdquo; (Alwyn Scott in &amp;ldquo;How Smart is a Neuron?&amp;rdquo; in A Review of Christof Kochs&amp;rsquo; &amp;ldquo;Biophysics of Computation&amp;rdquo; )&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Que les cons le restent!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Those who can &amp;ndash; do. Those who can&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ndash; teach. (H.L. Mencken). Those who cannot teach &amp;ndash; administrate. (Martin)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Under capitalism, man exploits man. Under communism, it&amp;rsquo;s just the opposite. (John Kenneth Galbraith)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Love is the triumph of imagination over intelligence. (H. L. Mencken)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The power of accurate observation is commonly called cynicism by those who have not got it. (George Bernard Shaw)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Remember, beneath every cynic there lies a romantic, and probably an injured one. (Glenn Beck)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If we see the light at the end of the tunnel, it&amp;rsquo;s the light of an oncoming train.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; Robert Lowell&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Any intelligent fool can make things bigger, more complex, and more violent. It takes a touch of genius &amp;ndash; and a lot of courage &amp;ndash; to move in the opposite direction&amp;rdquo;  &amp;ndash; Albert Einstein&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Je sais ce que je crois. Je continuerais à exprimer ce que je crois, et ce que je crois&amp;hellip; je crois que ce que je crois est bien.&amp;rdquo;- GWB&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Soudain, je ne sais comment, le cas fut subit, je n&amp;rsquo;eus loisir de le considérer, Panurge, sans autre chose dire, jette en pleine mer son mouton criant et bêlant. Tous les autres moutons, criant et bêlant en pareille intonation, commencèrent à se jeter et à sauter en mer après, à la file. La foule était à qui le premier y sauterait après leur compagnon. Il n&amp;rsquo;était pas possible de les en empêcher, comme vous savez du mouton le naturel, toujours suivre le premier, quelque part qu&amp;rsquo;il aille.&amp;rdquo; Rabelais&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Personne ne peut dire dans quel but l&amp;rsquo;homme a été amené en ce monde, ni quelle sera la destinée de l&amp;rsquo;espèce. Cependant, il y a de grands esprits qui ne vivent pas pour leur bien-être présent mais en vue d&amp;rsquo;une fin impersonnelle, comme un coureur qui s&amp;rsquo;épuiserait dans une course de relais, pour un trophée qu&amp;rsquo;il ignore et qu&amp;rsquo;un autre remportera.&amp;rdquo; Charles Morgan, Essai sur l&amp;rsquo;unité de l&amp;rsquo;esprit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Science sans conscience n&amp;rsquo;est que ruine de l&amp;rsquo;âme.&amp;rdquo;  (Rabelais, 1532)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Linux is only free if your time has no value.” (Jamie Zawinski)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Napoléon : Monsieur de Laplace, je ne trouve pas dans votre système mention de Dieu  ?    Laplace : Sire, je n&amp;rsquo;ai pas eu besoin de cette hypothèse. (d&amp;rsquo;autres savants ayant déploré que Laplace fasse l&amp;rsquo;économie d&amp;rsquo;une hypothèse qui avait justement &amp;ldquo;le mérite d&amp;rsquo;expliquer tout&amp;rdquo;, Laplace répondit cette fois-ci à l&amp;rsquo;Empereur :    Laplace : Cette hypothèse, Sire, explique en effet tout, mais ne permet de prédire rien. En tant que savant, je me dois de vous fournir des travaux permettant des prédictions &amp;ldquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The supreme goal of all theory is to make the irreducible basic elements as simple and as few as possible without having to surrender the adequate representation of a single datum of experience&amp;rdquo; often paraphrased as &amp;ldquo;Theories should be as simple as possible, but no simpler.&amp;rdquo; Albert Einstein (1933)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The surest sign of the existence of extra- terrestrial intelligence is that they never bothered to come down here and visit us!&amp;rdquo; Calvin&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;«Si tu manges le fruit d&amp;rsquo;un grand arbre, n&amp;rsquo;oublie jamais de remercier le vent!» &amp;ldquo;tradition orale bambara au Mali&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Lorsque vous avez éliminé l’impossible, ce qui reste, si improbable soit-il, est nécessairement la vérité.&amp;rdquo; - Arthur Conan Doyle - &amp;ldquo;Le signe des Quatre&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I have come to believe that the whole world is an enigma, a harmless enigma that is made terrible by our own mad attempt to interpret it as though it had an underlying truth.&amp;rdquo;  &amp;ndash; Umberto Eco&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nos idées doivent être aussi vastes que la nature pour pouvoir en rendre compte.&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.evene.fr/citations/auteur.php?ida=813&amp;amp;celebrite=arthur-conan-doyle|&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Arthur Conan Doyle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Tout le monde savait que ce truc là était impossible a faire. Jusqu&amp;rsquo;au jour ou est arrivé quelqu&amp;rsquo;un qui ne le savait pas, et qui l&amp;rsquo;a fait.&amp;rdquo; Winston Churchill&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ce proverbe, je l&amp;rsquo;ai sur le bout de la&amp;hellip; &amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; Manu (2006-01-23T19:34:16Z)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;When you can measure what you are speaking about and express it in numbers, you know something about it; but when you cannot measure it, when you cannot express it in numbers, your knowledge is of the meager and unsatisfactory kind.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Lord Kelvin&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I know you believe you understand what you think I said, but I am not sure you realize that what you heard is not what I meant. &amp;ldquo;Richard Nixon&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Try to understand everything, but believe nothing! &amp;ldquo;Unknown&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;George Walker Bush a propos de ses démentis sur la cocaïne, répond « I haven&amp;rsquo;t denied anything. »&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bayes maxim : &amp;ldquo;condition the joint probability on what we know and marginalize on what we don&amp;rsquo;t care&amp;rdquo; John Coughlan (in prob. models / kersten)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Monty Python&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Life of Brian&amp;rdquo;: {{{(Brian)-&amp;ldquo;You are all individuals!&amp;rdquo; (crowd)-&amp;ldquo;We are all individuals!&amp;rdquo;(Brian)-&amp;ldquo;You have to be different!&amp;rdquo; (crowd)-&amp;ldquo;Yes, we are all different!&amp;rdquo; (loner)-&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m not.&amp;rdquo;}}}&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Monty Python&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Life of Brian&amp;rdquo;: (Brian:) &amp;ldquo;You have to work it out for yourselves!&amp;rdquo; (Crowd:) &amp;ldquo;Yes, we have to work it out for ourselves&amp;hellip; (silence) Tell us more!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Combien d&amp;rsquo;autres corps célestes, outre ces comètes, se meuvent en secret sans jamais se montrer aux yeux des hommes. Dieu n&amp;rsquo;a pas fait toutes les choses pour l&amp;rsquo;homme.&amp;rdquo; Sénéque&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hawking&amp;rsquo;s principle for popularizations : &amp;ldquo;each math symbol reduces the potential readership by a factor r = &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Les ordinateurs sont trop fiables pour remplacer rellement les humains.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Prediction is very difficult, especially about the future. Niels Bohr&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;On peut vous le faire :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bien&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vite&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pour peu cher
Ne choisissez pas plus de deux options.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;s. v..s p..v.z c.mpr.ndr. c.l. v..s p..v.z .tr. d.v.l.ppé&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Intelligence artificielle : art de programmer les ordinateurs de sorte qu&amp;rsquo;ils se comportent comme ils le font dans les films.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;hypoaristerolactothérapie : méthode de dépannage des machines par le coup de pied en bas à gauche.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Le peu que je sais , c&amp;rsquo;est à mon ignorance que je le dois .GUITRY , Sacha&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;TOULET , Paul-Jean &amp;ldquo;Apprends àte connaître : tu t&amp;rsquo;aimeras moins . Et à connaître les autres , tu ne les aimeras plus.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Occam&amp;rsquo;s razor : &amp;ldquo;Accept the simplest explanation that fits the data.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;On two occasions, I have been asked [by members of Parliament], &amp;lsquo;Pray, Mr. Babbage, if you put into the machine wrong figures, will the right answers come out?&amp;rsquo; I am not able to rightly apprehend the kind of confusion of ideas that could provoke such a question.&amp;ldquo;&amp;ndash; Charles Babbage (1791-1871)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Reality is that which, when you stop believing in it, doesn&amp;rsquo;t go away&amp;rdquo;. Philip K. Dick&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Puisque ce désordre nous échappe, feignons d&amp;rsquo;en être l&amp;rsquo;organisateur. &amp;rdquo; Cocteau&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Non seulement la solution n&amp;rsquo;existe pas, mais en plus elle n&amp;rsquo;est pas unique.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Detection is, or ought to be, an exact science, and should be treated in the same cold and unemotional manner. You have attempted to tinge it with romanticism, which produces much the same effect as if you worked a love-story or an elopement into the fifth proposition of Euclid. &amp;ndash; SHERLOCK HOLMES &amp;ldquo;Sign of The Four&amp;rdquo;, Chapter 1
*
&amp;ldquo; Act without doing;
work without effort.
Think of the small as large
and the few as many.
Confront the difficult
while it is still easy;
accomplish the great task
by a series of small acts. &amp;ldquo; Lao-Tze&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Les mathématiques ne sont pas une moindre immensité que la mer&amp;rdquo; V. Hugo&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Le hasard n&amp;rsquo;est que la mesure de notre ignorance&amp;rdquo; Henri Poincaré, La science et l&amp;rsquo;hypothèse&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Je répugne toute religion qui ne se voit philosophe&amp;rdquo; Lolo Tseu&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
