<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Events on Novel visual computations</title>
    <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Events on Novel visual computations</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This material is presented to ensure timely dissemination of scholarly and technical work. Copyright and all rights therein are retained by authors or by other copyright holders. All persons copying this information are expected to adhere to the terms and constraints invoked by each author&#39;s copyright. In most cases, these works may not be reposted without the explicit permission of the copyright holder.
&lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Creative Commons License&#34; style=&#34;border-width:0&#34; src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/3.0/88x31.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This work is licensed under a &lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 3.0 Unported License&lt;/a&gt;
Please note that multiple distribution, publication or commercial usage of copyrighted papers included in this website would require submission of a permission request addressed to the journal in which the paper appeared.
</copyright>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Illusions et hallucinations visuelles : une porte sur la perception</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/2019-06-06-theconversation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/2019-06-06-theconversation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Publication d&amp;rsquo;un nouvel article généraliste autour des &amp;ldquo;Illusions et hallucinations visuelles&amp;rdquo; à découvrir sur le site &lt;a href=&#34;https://theconversation.com/illusions-et-hallucinations-visuelles-une-porte-sur-la-perception-117389&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;TheConversation&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;fr&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Illusions et hallucinations visuelles : une porte sur la perception &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/nOJFVRYDz7&#34;&gt;https://t.co/nOJFVRYDz7&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/HiBPHbKdSA&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/HiBPHbKdSA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Conversation France (@FR_Conversation) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/FR_Conversation/status/1136743272024612886?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;June 6, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Les objectifs sont :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– mieux comprendre la fonction de la perception visuelle en explorant certaines limites ;
– mieux comprendre l’importance de l’aspect dynamique de la perception ;
– mieux comprendre le rôle de l’action dans la perception.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;fr&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Les &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/illusions?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#illusions&lt;/a&gt; et &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/hallucinations?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#hallucinations&lt;/a&gt; nous informent sur les &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/perceptions?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#perceptions&lt;/a&gt; mais aussi sur la compréhension des mécanismes cérébraux.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Laurent Perrinet, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/imera_amu?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@imera_amu&lt;/a&gt;, nous explique comment et pourquoi une image peut tromper nos sens.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;🌪️&lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/5QSaezZonz&#34;&gt;https://t.co/5QSaezZonz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/neurosciences?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#neurosciences&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/cerveau?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#cerveau&lt;/a&gt;🧠 &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/t8ehsyoGt8&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/t8ehsyoGt8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Conversation France (@FR_Conversation) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/FR_Conversation/status/1136989689867620353?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;June 7, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Une version étendue est accessible sur le &lt;a href=&#34;https://laurentperrinet.github.io/2019-05_illusions-visuelles/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;repo GitHub&lt;/a&gt;, ainsi que les &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/laurentperrinet/2019-05_illusions-visuelles&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;sources&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical neuroscience Symposium on Active Inference at NeuroFrance 2019</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/2019-05-23-neurofrance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/2019-05-23-neurofrance/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;active-inference-bridging-theoretical-and-experimental-neurosciences-inference-active-un-pont-entre-neurosciences-théoriques-et-expérimentales&#34;&gt;Active Inference: Bridging theoretical and experimental neurosciences. / Inference Active: Un pont entre neurosciences théoriques et expérimentales.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.neurosciences.asso.fr/V2/colloques/SN19/index_en.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://neuro-marseille.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/capture-decran-2018-07-06-a-190423.png&#34; alt=&#34;Site NeuroFrance&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SYMPOSIUM S17&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When: 23.05.2019 11:00-13:00h&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When: Endoume 1+2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;s17-1-https-www-professionalabstracts-com-nf2019-iplanner-presentation-1397-active-inference-and-brain-computer-interfaces-inférence-active-et-interfaces-cerveau-machine&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.professionalabstracts.com/nf2019/iplanner/#/presentation/1397&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;S17.1&lt;/a&gt;  Active inference and Brain-Computer Interfaces / Inférence active et interfaces cerveau-machine&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mattout J. (Lyon, France), Mladenovic J. (Lyon, France), Frey J. (Bordeaux, France)3, Joffily M. (Lyon, France), Maby E. (Lyon, France), Lotte F. (Lyon, France)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brain-Computer Interfaces (BCIs) devices bypass natural pathways to connect the brain with a machine, directly. They may rely on invasive or non-invasive measures of brain activity and applications cover a large domain, mostly but not restricted to clinical ones. A major objective is to restore communication and autonomy in heavily motor impaired patients.
However, no BCI has made its way to a routinely used clinical application yet. One lead for improvement is to endow the machine with learning abilities so that it can optimize its decisions and adapt to changes in the user signals over time1. Several approaches have been proposed but a generic framework is still lacking to foster the development of efficient adaptive BCIs2.
Initially proposed to model perception, learning and action by the brain, the Active Inference (AI) framework offers great promises in that aim3. It rests on an explicit generative model of the environment. In BCI, from the machine&amp;rsquo;s point of view, brain signals play the role of sensory inputs on which the machine&amp;rsquo;s perception of mental states will be based. Furthermore, the machine builds up decisions and trades between different actions such as: go on observing, deciding to decide, correcting its previous action or moving on.
In this talk, I will present an instantiation of AI in the context of the EEG-based P300-speller BCI for communication, showing it can flexibly combine complementary adaptive features pertaining to both perception and action, and yield significant improvements as shown on realistic simulations. We will discuss perspectives to further extend the current model and performance as well as the challenges ahead to implement this framework online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mattout, J. Brain-Computer Interfaces: A Neuroscience Paradigm of Social Interaction? A Matter of Perspective. Frontiers in Human Neuroscience 6, (2012).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mladenovic, J., Mattout, J. &amp;amp; Lotte, F. A Generic Framework for Adaptive EEG-Based BCI Training and Operation. in Brain-computer interfaces handbook: technological and theoretical advances (eds. Nam, C. S., Nijholt, A. &amp;amp; Lotte, F.) Chapter 31 (Taylor &amp;amp; Francis, CRC Press, 2018).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Friston, K., Mattout, J. &amp;amp; Kilner, J. Action understanding and active inference. Biological Cybernetics 104, 137-160 (2011).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;s17-2-https-www-professionalabstracts-com-nf2019-iplanner-presentation-1398-comparing-active-inference-and-reinforcement-learning-models-of-a-go-nogo-task-and-their-relationships-to-striatal-dopamine-2-receptors-assessed-using-pet-comparaison-des-modèles-d-inférence-active-et-d-apprentissage-par-renforcement-dans-une-tâche-go-nogo-relation-avec-les-récepteurs-dopaminergiques-d2-striataux-évalués-par-tep&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.professionalabstracts.com/nf2019/iplanner/#/presentation/1398&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;S17.2&lt;/a&gt;  Comparing active inference and reinforcement learning models of a Go NoGo task and their relationships to striatal dopamine 2 receptors assessed using PET / Comparaison des modèles d&amp;rsquo;inférence active et d&amp;rsquo;apprentissage par renforcement dans une tâche Go / NoGo : relation avec les récepteurs dopaminergiques D2 striataux évalués par TEP&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;R. Adams (London)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.professionalabstracts.com/nf2019/iplanner/#/presentation/1398&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://www.professionalabstracts.com/nf2019/iplanner/#/presentation/1398&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adaptive behaviour includes the ability to choose actions that result in advantageous outcomes. It is key to survival and a fundamental function of nervous systems. Active inference (AI) and reinforcement learning (RL) are two influential models of how the brain might achieve this. A key AI parameter is the precision of beliefs about policies. Precision controls the stochasticity of action selection - similar to decision temperature in RL - and is thought to be encoded by striatal dopamine. 75 healthy subjects performed a &amp;lsquo;go/no-go&amp;rsquo; task, and we measured striatal dopamine &lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; receptor (D2/3R) availability in a subset of 25 using [11C]-(+)-PHNO positron emission tomography. In behavioural model comparison, RL performed best across the whole group but AI performed best in accurate subjects. D2/3R availability in the limbic striatum correlated with AI policy precision and also with RL irreducible decision &amp;lsquo;noise&amp;rsquo;. Limbic striatal D2/3R availability also correlated with AI Pavlovian prior beliefs - i.e. the respective probabilities of making or withholding actions in rewarding or loss-avoiding contexts - and the RL learning rate. These findings are consistent with the notion that occupancy of inhibitory striatal D2/3Rs controls the variability of action selection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;s17-3-https-www-professionalabstracts-com-nf2019-iplanner-presentation-1399-principles-and-psychophysics-of-active-inference-in-anticipating-a-dynamic-switching-probabilistic-bias-principes-et-psychophysique-de-l-inférence-active-dans-l-estimation-d-un-biais-dynamique-et-volatile-de-probabilité&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.professionalabstracts.com/nf2019/iplanner/#/presentation/1399&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;S17.3&lt;/a&gt;  Principles and psychophysics of active inference in anticipating a dynamic, switching probabilistic bias / Principes et psychophysique de l&amp;rsquo;inférence active dans l´estimation d&amp;rsquo;un biais dynamique et volatile de probabilité&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;L. Perrinet (Marseille)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;see more info on this &lt;a href=&#34;https://laurentperrinet.github.io/talk/2019-05-23-neurofrance/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;talk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;s17-4-https-www-professionalabstracts-com-nf2019-iplanner-presentation-1400-is-laziness-contagious-a-computational-approach-to-attitude-alignment-la-fainéantise-est-elle-contagieuse-une-approche-computationnelle-de-l-alignement-des-attitudes&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.professionalabstracts.com/nf2019/iplanner/#/presentation/1400&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;S17.4&lt;/a&gt;  Is laziness contagious? A computational approach to attitude alignment / La fainéantise est-elle contagieuse? Une approche computationnelle de l´alignement des attitudes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;J. Daunizeau (Paris)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do people learn from observing others´ attitudes, such as prudence, impatience or laziness? Rather than viewing these attitudes as examples of subjective and biologically entrenched personality traits, we assume that they derive from uncertain (and mostly implicit) beliefs about how to best weigh risks, delays and efforts in ensuing cost-benefit trade-offs. In this view, it is adaptive to update one´s belief after having observed others´ attitude, which provides valuable information regarding how to best behave in related difficult decision contexts. This is the starting point of our bayesian model of attitude alignment, which we derive in the light of recent neuroimaging findings. First, we disclose a few non-trivial predictions from this model. Second, we validate these predictions experimentally by profiling people´s prudence, impatience and laziness both before and after guessing a series of cost-benefit arbitrages performed by calibrated artificial agents (which are impersonating human individuals). Third, we extend these findings and assess attitude alignment in autistic individuals. Finally, we discuss the relevance and implications of this work, with a particular emphasis on the assessment of biases of social cognition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;s17-5-https-www-professionalabstracts-com-nf2019-iplanner-presentation-223-generative-bayesian-modeling-for-causal-inference-between-neural-activity-and-behavior-in-drosophila-larva&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.professionalabstracts.com/nf2019/iplanner/#/presentation/223&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;S17.5&lt;/a&gt;   Generative Bayesian modeling for causal inference between neural activity and behavior in Drosophila larva&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;C. Barre (Paris) (TBC)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A fundamental property of the central nervous system is its ability to select appropriate behavioral patterns or sequences of behavioral patterns in response to sensory cues, but what are the biological mechanisms underlying decision making? The Drosophila larva is an ideal animal model for reverse-engineering the neural processes underlying behavior. The full connectome of the larva brain has been imaged at the individual-synapse level using electron microscopy.
The host of genetic techniques available for Drosophila allows us to optogenetically manipulate over 1,500 of its roughly 12,000 neurons individually in freely behaving larvae.
This enables us to establish causal relationships between neural activity, and behavior at the fundamental level of individual neurons and neural connections.
We have access to video record of the individual behavior of ~3,000,000 larvae. We have identified 6 stereotypical behavioral patterns using a combination of supervised and unsupervised machine learning. The behavioral identified for the larva: crawl, turn, stop, crawl backward, hunch (retract the head), and roll (lateral slide). Each realization of a behavioral pattern is characterized by a different duration, amplitude, and velocity.
Here we present a generative model that extracts the behavior of wildtype larvae using Bayesian inference, and interprets behavioral changes following neuron activation or inactivation from large-scale experimental screens. Fig. shows the average behavior of 10,000 larvae over time in a screen where a single neuron is activated at t=30s. A clear change in behavior is seen following activation is seen which is well captured by the model, illustrating its accuracy.
The generative model enables us to robustly detect behavioral modifications as significant deviations of the patterns in the larvae&amp;rsquo;s sequence of activities from their equilibrium behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;neurofrance-marseille-capitale-des-neurosciences&#34;&gt;NeuroFrance: Marseille, capitale des neurosciences&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Du  22 au 24 mai 2019 au Palais des congrès de Marseille (Parc Chanot), près de 1300 chercheurs, cliniciens et étudiants venus du monde entier partageront leurs travaux lors de NeuroFrance 2019, colloque international organisé par la Société des Neurosciences.Au total, 8 conférences plénières, 42 symposiums, 6 sessions spécialisées, 525 communications affichées, ainsi qu’une exposition avec 42 entreprises et sociétés de biotechnologies, feront de ce colloque un moment exceptionnel pour mettre en lumière les avancées majeures scientifiques et technologiques sur le fonctionnement du cerveau. Vous pourrez aussi découvrir le &amp;ldquo;Neurovillage&amp;rdquo; qui permettra de vous immerger au cœur des innovations neuroscientifiques marseillaises, ainsi que  l’exposition  « L’Art en tête », composée de cinq œuvres originales créées par des artistes et des scientifiques. Plusieurs événements seront également proposés autour du colloque pour le grand public comme pour les chercheurs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elasticité dynamique</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/2016-06-02_elasticite/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/2016-06-02_elasticite/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;elasticité-dynamique-fondation-vasarely-à-aix-en-provence&#34;&gt;Elasticité dynamique @  Fondation Vasarely à Aix-en-Provence&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2016, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/NaturalPatterns/elasticite&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://github.com/NaturalPatterns/elasticite&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;L&amp;rsquo;installation &amp;ldquo;Elasticité dynamique&amp;rdquo; agit comme un filtre et génère de nouveaux espaces démultipliés, comme un empilement quasi infini d&amp;rsquo;horizons.
Par principe de réflexion, la pièce absorbe l&amp;rsquo;image de l&amp;rsquo;environnement et accumule les points de vue ; le mouvement permanent requalifie continuellement ce qui est regardé et entendu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DIMENSIONS : 3 m de haut 5 m de large, INOX POLI MIROIR / ALUMINIUM / ACIER / MOTEURS / PROGRAMME TEMPS RÉEL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LIEU : Fondation Vasarely&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;EXPOSITION : &lt;a href=&#34;http://ondesparalleles.org/projets/trame-elasticite-vasarely/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Multiplicité, Fondation Vasarely dans le cadre de l’Hommage à Victor Vasarely&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;EXPOSITION : DU 2 juin au 2 octobre 2016&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VIDEOS : &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/198189587&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://vimeo.com/198189587&lt;/a&gt; Crédits :  © Etienne Rey&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Composé d’une succession de lames de miroirs, verticales et rotatives, l’installation Trame se joue des reflets et de la démultiplication de l’espace, offrant au spectateur une multiplicité de points de vue dans lesquels il peut se perdre à loisir. Par un effet de « porosité » recherché par l’artiste, le dispositif dialogue intensément avec les Intégrations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Devant l’œuvre en constante métamorphose, l’alphabet plastique de Vasarely se recompose ainsi à l’infini comme un jeu de construction renouvelable. Dans cette œuvre, Etienne Rey explore en profondeur les possibilités offertes par le mouvement, la lumière, et surtout l’interaction entre l’œuvre, le public et l’espace, ouvrant sur de nouveaux rapports sensibles et sensoriels au monde.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Texte : Véronique Baton)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;elasticité-dynamique-104-paris&#34;&gt;Elasticité dynamique @  104 (Paris)&lt;/h1&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//player.vimeo.com/video/150813922&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LIEU:: NEMO, BIENNALE INTERNATIONALE DES ARTS NUMERIQUES - CENTQUATRE - 104&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;EXPOSITION : &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.104.fr/programmation/evenement.html?evenement=518&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Prosopopées : Quand les objets prennent vie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VERNISSAGE : SAMEDI 5 DÉCEMBRE 14h &amp;gt; 23h30&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;EXPOSITION : DU 6 DÉCEMBRE 2015 AU 18 JANVIER 2016&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VIDEOS : &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/150654250&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://vimeo.com/150654250&lt;/a&gt; : installation;  &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/146242233&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://vimeo.com/146242233&lt;/a&gt; : simulation, Crédits : Elasticité dynamique © Etienne Rey, Adagp Paris 2015&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/UvE3ysXieSk&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;||&lt;tablestyle=&#34;width: 90%; float: center; margin-left:20px; margin-right:20px; border-style: 0px;  font-size: 10pt;&#34;&gt;{{&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lafriche.org/public_data/diapo/resident/1454686884/desk/2._elasticite_dynamique-etienne_rey-photoquentin_chevrier_pour_art2m_et_arcadi_ile_de_france.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.lafriche.org/public_data/diapo/resident/1454686884/desk/2._elasticite_dynamique-etienne_rey-photoquentin_chevrier_pour_art2m_et_arcadi_ile_de_france.jpg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Elasticité dynamique est composée des pièces Expansion, Trame et Lignes sonores. Volume hexagonal en miroir de 7 mètres de diamètre, Expansion fonctionne comme une chambre d&#39;écho. A l&#39;intérieur de ce volume se situe Trame. Constituée de 25 lames de miroir en rotation, cette pièce réoriente continuellement le regard. Quant à Lignes sonores, elle est formée de quatre monolithes orientés vers Expansion et émet des sons qui se réorientent en fonction du mouvement des lames. (© Etienne Rey, Adagp Paris 2015)&#39;&#39;|width=&amp;quot;100%&amp;quot;}}Elasticité dynamique est composée des pièces Expansion, Trame et Lignes sonores. &amp;lt;&amp;lt;BR&amp;gt;&amp;gt; Volume hexagonal en miroir de 7 mètres de diamètre, Expansion fonctionne comme une chambre d&#39;écho. A l&#39;intérieur de ce volume se situe Trame. Constituée de 25 lames de miroir en rotation, cette pièce réoriente continuellement le regard. Quant à Lignes sonores, elle est formée de quatre monolithes orientés vers Expansion et émet des sons qui se réorientent en fonction du mouvement des lames. &amp;lt;&amp;lt;BR&amp;gt;&amp;gt;(© Etienne Rey, Adagp Paris 2015)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;equipe&#34;&gt;EQUIPE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Etienne Rey : Artiste plasticien&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wilfried Wendling : Compositeur&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Laurent Perrinet : Chercheur en Neurosciences à l’INT / CNRS-AMU&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Atelier Ni : Accompagnement conception&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gauthier Le Rouzic : Électronique&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lucie Evans : Assistante&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remerciements : Guillaume Stagnaro&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;production-déléguée&#34;&gt;PRODUCTION DÉLÉGUÉE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Seconde Nature&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;soutiens&#34;&gt;SOUTIENS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DRAC PACA _aide individuelle à la création&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;REGION PACA _CAC art visuel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;co-production&#34;&gt;CO-PRODUCTION&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ARCADI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;La Muse en Circuit. Centre National de Création Musicale&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CNRS-AMU / INT, Institut de Neurosciences de la Timone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Instabilité (series) @ Art-O-Rama</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/2018-09-09_artorama/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/2018-09-09_artorama/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;instabilité-series&#34;&gt;Instabilité (series)&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;installation-sérigraphie-dessin-mural-lumière-2018-guest-artist-mécènes-du-sud-art-o-rama-fair-marseille-i-2018&#34;&gt;Installation (sérigraphie, dessin mural, lumière), 2018;  Guest artist, Mécènes du Sud / Art-O-Rama (Fair), Marseille I 2018&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mécènes du Sud invite chaque année un artiste lauréat pour concevoir un stand-projet au sein du salon d’art contemporain ART-O-RAMA  : &amp;ldquo; Le travail d&amp;rsquo;Etienne Rey, lauréat 2011, explore la notion même d&amp;rsquo;espace. Il détourne des phénomènes physiques pour faire surgir par des biais perceptifs une conscience &amp;ldquo;d&amp;rsquo;être là&amp;rdquo;. Ses installations sont expérientielles par nature. Elles ne proposent pas une expérience elles la contiennent. Ce sont des oeuvres actives qui impliquent présence et espace. Instabilités, l&amp;rsquo;ensemble présenté ici, issu de recherches en cours de développement, met en tension espace et temps dans une expérience vibratoire. Chaos et cristal attisent des forces instables dans un rapport de contraintes qui détermine la complexité des oeuvres présentées.&amp;rdquo; Bénédicte Chevallier&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;En collaboration avec le chercheur Laurent Perrinet, CNRS-AMU / Institut de Neurosciences de la Timone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;links-liens&#34;&gt;Links / Liens:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ART-O-RAMA - &lt;a href=&#34;http://art-o-rama.fr/en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://art-o-rama.fr/en&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lemonde.fr/argent/article/2018/08/19/avec-art-o-rama-marseille-se-demarque-sur-le-marche-de-l-art_5343904_1657007.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://www.lemonde.fr/argent/article/2018/08/19/avec-art-o-rama-marseille-se-demarque-sur-le-marche-de-l-art_5343904_1657007.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.apollo-magazine.com/why-manifesta-makes-sense-in-marseille/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://www.apollo-magazine.com/why-manifesta-makes-sense-in-marseille/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Retour par &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.enrevenantdelexpo.com/2018/09/07/retour-sur-art-o-rama-2018-j1-marseille-1er-partie/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;En revenant de l&amp;rsquo;expo !&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i0.wp.com/www.enrevenantdelexpo.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/Art-O-Rama-2018-M%C3%A9c%C3%A8nes-du-Sud-%C3%89ienne-Rey-01.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Sortie modèle OptimalPacking&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SALON INTERNATIONAL D&amp;rsquo;ART CONTEMPORAIN ART-O-RAMA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SALON : 31 AOÛT &amp;gt; 2 SEPTEMBRE 2018&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;EXPOSITION &amp;gt; 9 SEPTEMBRE 2018&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ESPACE PARTENAIRES - J1, QUAI DE LA JOLIETTE, MARSEILLE 2e&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proverbes Et Citations</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/proverbes-et-citations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/proverbes-et-citations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I do know what time is,&amp;rdquo; Tubby declared. He paused. &amp;ldquo;Time,&amp;rdquo; he added slowly &amp;ndash; &amp;ldquo;time is what keeps everything from happening at once. I know that&amp;ndash;I seen it in print too.&amp;rdquo; (Ray Cummings)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You don’t see it because it’s there, it’s there because you see it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ni rire, ni pleurer, ni haïr, mais comprendre&amp;rdquo; (Baruch Spinoza)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;For years there has been a theory that millions of monkeys typing at random on millions of typewriters would reproduce the entire works of Shakespeare. The Internet has proven this theory to be untrue.&amp;rdquo; (???, ???)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Je me suis endormie, ce matin/en pensant/sur tes lèvres.&amp;rdquo;  (Anonyme, sur les murs, Marseille, 2017)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If you can look into the seeds of time, And say which grain will grow and which will not; Speak&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; (Shakespeare, Macbeth, Act I, Scene 3)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Here, too, the honorable finds its due, and there are tears for passing things; here, too, things mortal touch the mind.&amp;rdquo; (Virgil, Aeneid, 29-19 BC)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Man&amp;rsquo;s maturity is to have regained the seriousness that he had as a child at play.&amp;rdquo; (Friedrich Nietzsche)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There are 10 types of people in the world. Those who understand binary, those who don&amp;rsquo;t, those who weren&amp;rsquo;t expecting a base 8 joke, and 5 other types of people.&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;http://unix.stackexchange.com/questions/178162/why-does-bash-think-016-1-15&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;John Story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ce qui fut se refait; tout coule comme une eau / Et rien dessous le Ciel ne se voit de nouveau/ Mais la forme se change en une autre nouvelle/ Et ce changement-là. Vivre au monde s&amp;rsquo;appelle&amp;rdquo; - Ronsard, Hymnes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hanlon&amp;rsquo;s Razor: Never attribute to malice what is adequately explained by stupidity.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Essentially, all models are wrong, but some are useful.&amp;rdquo; &amp;mdash; Box, George E. P.; Norman R. Draper (1987). Empirical Model-Building and Response Surfaces, p. 424, Wiley. ISBN 0471810339&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Computers were around for 50 years before we figured out how to create the internet for example.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;In sum, the physicist can never subject an isolated hypothesis to experimental test, but only a whole group of hypotheses; when the experiment is in disagreement with his predictions, what he learns is that at least one of the hypotheses constituting this group is unacceptable and ought to be modified; but the experiment does not designate which one should be changed.&amp;rdquo; (P. Duhem, The Aim and Structure of Physical Theory, 1914)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Un bon maître a ce souci constant : enseigner à se passer de lui.&amp;rdquo; - André Gide&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Truth in science can be defined as the working hypothesis best suited to open the way to the next better one.”(Konrad Lorenz)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;“all motion is illusion” (Zeno of Elea, 490 BC )&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Be humble for you are made of dung. Be noble for you are made of stars.&amp;rdquo; (Serbian proverb)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;voir des objets ne consiste pas à en extraire des traits visuels, mais à guider visuellement l&amp;rsquo;action dirigée vers eux.&amp;rdquo;  (Francisco Varela in &amp;ldquo;L&amp;rsquo;inscription corporelle de l&amp;rsquo;esprit&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;la mémoire n’est pas faite pour se rappeler du passé mais pour prédire le futur.&amp;rdquo; (&lt;a href=&#34;http://dpea-archi.philo.over-blog.com/article-interview-de-alain-berthoz-par-thierry-paquot-61601814.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Alain Berthoz&lt;/a&gt; , 2010)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the days when the Sussman was a novice, Minsky once came to him as he sat hacking at the PDP-6. &amp;ldquo;What are you doing?&amp;rdquo;, asked Minsky. &amp;ldquo;I am training a randomly wired neural net to play Tic-tac-toe&amp;rdquo;, Sussman replied. &amp;ldquo;Why is the net wired randomly?&amp;rdquo;, asked Minsky. &amp;ldquo;I do not want it to have any preconceptions of how to play&amp;rdquo;, Sussman said. Minsky then shut his eyes. &amp;ldquo;Why do you close your eyes?&amp;rdquo; Sussman asked his teacher. &amp;ldquo;So that the room will be empty.&amp;rdquo; At that moment, Sussman was enlightened.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter how beautiful your theory is, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter how smart you are. If it doesn&amp;rsquo;t agree with experiment, it&amp;rsquo;s wrong.&amp;rdquo; Richard P. Feynman&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Think of the image of the world in a convex mirror. &amp;hellip; A well-made convex mirror of moderate aperture represents the objects in front of it as apparently solid and in fixed positions behind its surface. But the images of the distant horizon and of the sun in the sky lie behind the mirror at a limited distance, equal to its focal length. Between these and the surface of the mirror are found the images of all the other objects before it, but the images are diminished and flattened in proportion to the distance of their objects from the mirror. &amp;hellip; Yet every straight line or plane in the outer world is represented by a straight line or plane in the image. The image of a man measuring with a rule a straight line from the mirror, would contract more and more the farther he went, but with his shrunken rule the man in the image would count out exactly the same results as in the outer world, all lines of sight in the mirror would be represented by straight lines of sight in the mirror. In short, I do not see how men in the mirror are to discover that their bodies are not rigid solids and their experiences good examples of the correctness of Euclidean axioms. But if they could look out upon our world as we look into theirs without overstepping the boundary, they must declare it to be a picture in a spherical mirror, and would speak of us just as we speak of them; and if two inhabitants of the different worlds could communicate with one another, neither, as far as I can see, would be able to convince the other that he had the true, the other the distorted, relation. Indeed I cannot see that such a question would have any meaning at all, so long as mechanical considerations are not mixed up with it.&amp;rdquo; — Hermann von Helmholtz In &amp;lsquo;On the Origin and Significance of Geometrical Axioms,&amp;rdquo; Popular Scientific Lectures&amp;lt; Second Series (1881), 57-59. In Robert  Moritz, Memorabilia Mathematica (1914), 357-358.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Whoever, in the pursuit of science, seeks after immediate practical utility, may generally rest assured that he will seek in vain.&amp;rdquo; — Hermann von Helmholtz, Edmund Atkinson (trans.), Popular Lectures on Scientific Subjects: First Series (1883), 29&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;« Au départ, l’art du puzzle semble un art bref, un art mince, tout entier contenu dans un maigre enseignement de la Gestalttheorie : l’objet visé — qu’il s’agisse d’un acte perceptif, d’un apprentissage, d’un système physiologique ou, dans le cas qui nous occupe, d’un puzzle en bois — n’est pas une somme d’éléments qu’il faudrait d’abord isoler et analyser, mais un ensemble, c’est à dire une forme, une structure : l’élément ne préexiste pas à l’ensemble, il n’est ni plus immédiat ni plus ancien, ce ne sont pas les éléments qui déterminent l’ensemble, mais l’ensemble qui détermine les éléments : la connaissance du tout et de ses lois, de l’ensemble et de sa structure, ne saurait être déduite de la connaissance séparée des parties qui le composent : cela veut dire qu’on peut regarder une pièce d’un puzzle pendant trois jours et croire tout savoir de sa configuration et de sa couleur sans avoir le moins du monde avancé : seule compte la possibilité de relier cette pièce à d’autres pièces et, en ce sens, il y a quelque chose de commun entre l’art du puzzle et l’art du go ; seules les pièces rassemblées prendront un caractère lisible, prendront un sens : considérée isolément, une pièce d’un puzzle ne veut rien dire ; elle est seulement question impossible, défi opaque ; mais à peine a-t-on réussi, au terme de plusieurs minutes d’essais et d’erreurs, ou en une demi-seconde prodigieusement inspirée, à la connecter à l’une de ses voisines, que la pièce disparaît, cesse d’exister en tant que pièce : l’intense difficulté qui a précédé ce rapprochement, et que le mot puzzle — énigme — désigne si bien en anglais, non seulement n’a plus de raison d’être, mais semble n’en avoir jamais eu, tant elle est devenue évidence : les deux pièces miraculeusement réunies n’en font plus qu’une, à son tour source d’erreur, d’hésitation, de désarroi et d’attente. » (PEREC Georges, La vie mode d’emploi, Éditions Hachette, 1978, pp. 235-236.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;there&amp;rsquo;s really a trend toward ATLs ( Acronyms of Three Letters).&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;In theory there is no difference between theory and practice. In practice there is.&amp;rdquo; Yogi Berra&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Les décorations, c&amp;rsquo;est comme les bombes, ça tombe toujours sur ceux qui ne les méritent pas&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lemonde.fr/societe/article/2010/03/22/proces-viguier-deux-hommes-en-colere_1322481_3224_1.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Me Dupond-Moretti&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Science is what we understand well enough to explain to a computer. Art is everything else we do.&amp;rdquo; D. Knuth, foreword to &amp;ldquo;A=B&amp;rdquo; (1995)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;les cons ça ose tout et c&amp;rsquo;est même à ça qu&amp;rsquo;on les reconnaît&amp;rdquo; (Audiard)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;All generalisations are dangerous, including this one.&amp;rdquo; (Alexandre Dumas)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Il vaut mieux mobiliser son intelligence sur des conneries que mobiliser sa connerie sur des choses intelligentes.&amp;rdquo; Jacques Rouxel&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Nothing in biology makes sense except in the light of evolution&amp;rdquo;. (Theodosius Dobzhansky, 1900–1975)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Copy from one, it’s plagiarism; copy from two, it’s research.&amp;rdquo; (Wilson Mizner)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;In the past the man has been first, in the future the system must be first.&amp;rdquo; (F. Taylor)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;L&amp;rsquo;autorité n&amp;rsquo;admet que deux rôles : le bourreau et la victime, transforme les gens en poupées qui ne connaissent plus que peur et haine, tandis que la culture plonge dans les abysses. L&amp;rsquo;autorité déforme ses enfants et change leur amour en un combat de coq&amp;hellip; L&amp;rsquo;effondrement de l&amp;rsquo;autorité aura des répercussions sur le bureau, l&amp;rsquo;église et l&amp;rsquo;école. Tout est lié. L&amp;rsquo;égalité et la liberté ne sont pas des luxes que l&amp;rsquo;on écarte impunément. Sans ceux-ci, l&amp;rsquo;ordre ne peut survivre longtemps sans se rapprocher de profondeurs inimaginables.&amp;rdquo; Alan Moore, &lt;a href=&#34;http://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/V_pour_Vendetta&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;V pour Vendetta&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;In a widely circulated joke [from the days of the first computer], a group of engineers assemble the most powerful computer that had ever been conceived and ask it the ultimate question: Is there a God? After several tense minutes of clicking and clacking and flashing of lights, a card pops out which reads: There is &amp;ldquo;now&amp;rdquo;.&amp;rdquo; (Alwyn Scott in &amp;ldquo;How Smart is a Neuron?&amp;rdquo; in A Review of Christof Kochs&amp;rsquo; &amp;ldquo;Biophysics of Computation&amp;rdquo; )&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Que les cons le restent!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Those who can &amp;ndash; do. Those who can&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ndash; teach. (H.L. Mencken). Those who cannot teach &amp;ndash; administrate. (Martin)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Under capitalism, man exploits man. Under communism, it&amp;rsquo;s just the opposite. (John Kenneth Galbraith)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Love is the triumph of imagination over intelligence. (H. L. Mencken)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The power of accurate observation is commonly called cynicism by those who have not got it. (George Bernard Shaw)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Remember, beneath every cynic there lies a romantic, and probably an injured one. (Glenn Beck)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If we see the light at the end of the tunnel, it&amp;rsquo;s the light of an oncoming train.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; Robert Lowell&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Any intelligent fool can make things bigger, more complex, and more violent. It takes a touch of genius &amp;ndash; and a lot of courage &amp;ndash; to move in the opposite direction&amp;rdquo;  &amp;ndash; Albert Einstein&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Je sais ce que je crois. Je continuerais à exprimer ce que je crois, et ce que je crois&amp;hellip; je crois que ce que je crois est bien.&amp;rdquo;- GWB&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Soudain, je ne sais comment, le cas fut subit, je n&amp;rsquo;eus loisir de le considérer, Panurge, sans autre chose dire, jette en pleine mer son mouton criant et bêlant. Tous les autres moutons, criant et bêlant en pareille intonation, commencèrent à se jeter et à sauter en mer après, à la file. La foule était à qui le premier y sauterait après leur compagnon. Il n&amp;rsquo;était pas possible de les en empêcher, comme vous savez du mouton le naturel, toujours suivre le premier, quelque part qu&amp;rsquo;il aille.&amp;rdquo; Rabelais&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Personne ne peut dire dans quel but l&amp;rsquo;homme a été amené en ce monde, ni quelle sera la destinée de l&amp;rsquo;espèce. Cependant, il y a de grands esprits qui ne vivent pas pour leur bien-être présent mais en vue d&amp;rsquo;une fin impersonnelle, comme un coureur qui s&amp;rsquo;épuiserait dans une course de relais, pour un trophée qu&amp;rsquo;il ignore et qu&amp;rsquo;un autre remportera.&amp;rdquo; Charles Morgan, Essai sur l&amp;rsquo;unité de l&amp;rsquo;esprit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Science sans conscience n&amp;rsquo;est que ruine de l&amp;rsquo;âme.&amp;rdquo;  (Rabelais, 1532)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Linux is only free if your time has no value.” (Jamie Zawinski)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Napoléon : Monsieur de Laplace, je ne trouve pas dans votre système mention de Dieu  ?    Laplace : Sire, je n&amp;rsquo;ai pas eu besoin de cette hypothèse. (d&amp;rsquo;autres savants ayant déploré que Laplace fasse l&amp;rsquo;économie d&amp;rsquo;une hypothèse qui avait justement &amp;ldquo;le mérite d&amp;rsquo;expliquer tout&amp;rdquo;, Laplace répondit cette fois-ci à l&amp;rsquo;Empereur :    Laplace : Cette hypothèse, Sire, explique en effet tout, mais ne permet de prédire rien. En tant que savant, je me dois de vous fournir des travaux permettant des prédictions &amp;ldquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The supreme goal of all theory is to make the irreducible basic elements as simple and as few as possible without having to surrender the adequate representation of a single datum of experience&amp;rdquo; often paraphrased as &amp;ldquo;Theories should be as simple as possible, but no simpler.&amp;rdquo; Albert Einstein (1933)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The surest sign of the existence of extra- terrestrial intelligence is that they never bothered to come down here and visit us!&amp;rdquo; Calvin&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;«Si tu manges le fruit d&amp;rsquo;un grand arbre, n&amp;rsquo;oublie jamais de remercier le vent!» &amp;ldquo;tradition orale bambara au Mali&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Lorsque vous avez éliminé l’impossible, ce qui reste, si improbable soit-il, est nécessairement la vérité.&amp;rdquo; - Arthur Conan Doyle - &amp;ldquo;Le signe des Quatre&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I have come to believe that the whole world is an enigma, a harmless enigma that is made terrible by our own mad attempt to interpret it as though it had an underlying truth.&amp;rdquo;  &amp;ndash; Umberto Eco&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nos idées doivent être aussi vastes que la nature pour pouvoir en rendre compte.&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.evene.fr/citations/auteur.php?ida=813&amp;amp;celebrite=arthur-conan-doyle|&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Arthur Conan Doyle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Tout le monde savait que ce truc là était impossible a faire. Jusqu&amp;rsquo;au jour ou est arrivé quelqu&amp;rsquo;un qui ne le savait pas, et qui l&amp;rsquo;a fait.&amp;rdquo; Winston Churchill&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ce proverbe, je l&amp;rsquo;ai sur le bout de la&amp;hellip; &amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; Manu (2006-01-23T19:34:16Z)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;When you can measure what you are speaking about and express it in numbers, you know something about it; but when you cannot measure it, when you cannot express it in numbers, your knowledge is of the meager and unsatisfactory kind.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Lord Kelvin&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I know you believe you understand what you think I said, but I am not sure you realize that what you heard is not what I meant. &amp;ldquo;Richard Nixon&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Try to understand everything, but believe nothing! &amp;ldquo;Unknown&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;George Walker Bush a propos de ses démentis sur la cocaïne, répond « I haven&amp;rsquo;t denied anything. »&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bayes maxim : &amp;ldquo;condition the joint probability on what we know and marginalize on what we don&amp;rsquo;t care&amp;rdquo; John Coughlan (in prob. models / kersten)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Monty Python&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Life of Brian&amp;rdquo;: {{{(Brian)-&amp;ldquo;You are all individuals!&amp;rdquo; (crowd)-&amp;ldquo;We are all individuals!&amp;rdquo;(Brian)-&amp;ldquo;You have to be different!&amp;rdquo; (crowd)-&amp;ldquo;Yes, we are all different!&amp;rdquo; (loner)-&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m not.&amp;rdquo;}}}&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Monty Python&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Life of Brian&amp;rdquo;: (Brian:) &amp;ldquo;You have to work it out for yourselves!&amp;rdquo; (Crowd:) &amp;ldquo;Yes, we have to work it out for ourselves&amp;hellip; (silence) Tell us more!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Combien d&amp;rsquo;autres corps célestes, outre ces comètes, se meuvent en secret sans jamais se montrer aux yeux des hommes. Dieu n&amp;rsquo;a pas fait toutes les choses pour l&amp;rsquo;homme.&amp;rdquo; Sénéque&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hawking&amp;rsquo;s principle for popularizations : &amp;ldquo;each math symbol reduces the potential readership by a factor r = &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Les ordinateurs sont trop fiables pour remplacer rellement les humains.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Prediction is very difficult, especially about the future. Niels Bohr&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;On peut vous le faire :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bien&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vite&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pour peu cher
Ne choisissez pas plus de deux options.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;s. v..s p..v.z c.mpr.ndr. c.l. v..s p..v.z .tr. d.v.l.ppé&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Intelligence artificielle : art de programmer les ordinateurs de sorte qu&amp;rsquo;ils se comportent comme ils le font dans les films.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;hypoaristerolactothérapie : méthode de dépannage des machines par le coup de pied en bas à gauche.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Le peu que je sais , c&amp;rsquo;est à mon ignorance que je le dois .GUITRY , Sacha&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;TOULET , Paul-Jean &amp;ldquo;Apprends àte connaître : tu t&amp;rsquo;aimeras moins . Et à connaître les autres , tu ne les aimeras plus.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Occam&amp;rsquo;s razor : &amp;ldquo;Accept the simplest explanation that fits the data.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;On two occasions, I have been asked [by members of Parliament], &amp;lsquo;Pray, Mr. Babbage, if you put into the machine wrong figures, will the right answers come out?&amp;rsquo; I am not able to rightly apprehend the kind of confusion of ideas that could provoke such a question.&amp;ldquo;&amp;ndash; Charles Babbage (1791-1871)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Reality is that which, when you stop believing in it, doesn&amp;rsquo;t go away&amp;rdquo;. Philip K. Dick&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Puisque ce désordre nous échappe, feignons d&amp;rsquo;en être l&amp;rsquo;organisateur. &amp;rdquo; Cocteau&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Non seulement la solution n&amp;rsquo;existe pas, mais en plus elle n&amp;rsquo;est pas unique.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Detection is, or ought to be, an exact science, and should be treated in the same cold and unemotional manner. You have attempted to tinge it with romanticism, which produces much the same effect as if you worked a love-story or an elopement into the fifth proposition of Euclid. &amp;ndash; SHERLOCK HOLMES &amp;ldquo;Sign of The Four&amp;rdquo;, Chapter 1
*
&amp;ldquo; Act without doing;
work without effort.
Think of the small as large
and the few as many.
Confront the difficult
while it is still easy;
accomplish the great task
by a series of small acts. &amp;ldquo; Lao-Tze&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Les mathématiques ne sont pas une moindre immensité que la mer&amp;rdquo; V. Hugo&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Le hasard n&amp;rsquo;est que la mesure de notre ignorance&amp;rdquo; Henri Poincaré, La science et l&amp;rsquo;hypothèse&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Je répugne toute religion qui ne se voit philosophe&amp;rdquo; Lolo Tseu&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sans gravité – une poétique de l’air</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/2019-06-22_ardemone/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/2019-06-22_ardemone/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//player.vimeo.com/video/317504725&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;h1 id=&#34;densité-flou-2019&#34;&gt;« Densité flou » (2019)&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.enrevenantdelexpo.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Étienne-Rey-Horizon-faille-Densité-flou-2019-Sans-gravité-une-poétique-de-l’air-à-Ardenome-Avignon-02.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Étienne Rey - Horizon faille - Densité flou, 2019 - Sans gravité - une poétique de l’air à - Ardenome - Avignon&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;tension-superficielle-2019&#34;&gt;« Tension superficielle » (2019)&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i1.wp.com/www.enrevenantdelexpo.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/%C3%89tienne-Rey-Horizon-faille-Tension-superficielle-2019-Sans-gravit%C3%A9-une-po%C3%A9tique-de-l%E2%80%99air-%C3%A0-Ardenome-Avignon-00_1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Étienne Rey – Horizon faille – Tension superficielle, 2019 – Sans gravité – une poétique de l’air à – Ardenome – Avignon&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;dans-le-cadre-de-sans-gravité-une-poétique-de-l-air-etienne-rey-mathilde-lavenne-hugo-deverchère-edith-dekyndt-23-mars-22-juin-2019&#34;&gt;dans le cadre de &amp;ldquo;SANS GRAVITÉ, UNE POÉTIQUE DE L&amp;rsquo;AIR - ETIENNE REY / MATHILDE LAVENNE / HUGO DEVERCHÈRE / EDITH DEKYNDT - 23 MARS &amp;gt; 22 JUIN 2019&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sans Gravité a été conçue par EDIS dans le cadre de “Chroniques, Biennale des Imaginaires Numériques”, qui réunit un ensemble d’institutions culturelles de la Région PACA.
Après Aix-Marseille, l’Ardenome à Avignon est la seconde étape
de ce parcours régional.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Horizon faille est une installation globale qui cherche à défier la gravité de la nature. Prenant appui sur deux notions dont l’artiste en a fait ses motifs principaux - les failles du paysage et l’immatérielle ligne d’horizon. La notion de faille exprime la fracture, au sens géologique. Elle est à considérer comme un interstice, une zone de transformation, un passage d’un état à un autre. De même, l’horizon scinde la terre du ciel dans une tentative de géométrisation de l’univers, de mise en espace des éléments naturels. Intouchable ligne de partage, ce filin tendu désigne aussi le seuil de vision du paysage. C’est la ligne imaginaire qui se forme à partir de notre position dans l’espace. Elle est ce qui échappe à la vue ou à la représentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;L’ensemble de ces œuvres résonnent en échos visuels les unes avec les autres. Elles décrivent des mouvements, des points de rupture, forment des zones de passage, explorent des états de métamorphose issus d’un paysage initial dont les perspectives ont été dépliés. En parcourant du regard ces différentes propositions plastiques, le visiteur prend conscience de l’espace qui l’entoure et le trouble à la fois. Un espace élastique, démultiplicateur qui lui offre une diversité d’angles dans lesquels il peut se perdre à loisir, comme en état d’apesanteur. Le monde n’est pas figé, il est une dérive constante, une recomposition permanente.
Véronique Baton&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Accompagnement Réalisation : Atelier Ni et Guillaume Stagnaro&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Variable Density et Tension Superficielle en collaboration avec Laurent Perrinet, chercheur Institut de neurosciences de la Timone, INT.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tirage sérigraphique Atelier Tchikebe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;links-liens&#34;&gt;Links / Liens:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;ardemone &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ardenome.fr/sans-gravite-ardenome-chroniques&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://www.ardenome.fr/sans-gravite-ardenome-chroniques&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Retour par &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.enrevenantdelexpo.com/2019/05/17/sans-gravite-une-poetique-de-air-ardenome-avignon/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;En revenant de l&amp;rsquo;expo !&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;SALON INTERNATIONAL D&amp;rsquo;ART CONTEMPORAIN ART-O-RAMA&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;SALON : 31 AOÛT &amp;gt; 2 SEPTEMBRE 2018&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;EXPOSITION &amp;gt; 9 SEPTEMBRE 2018&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;ESPACE PARTENAIRES - J1, QUAI DE LA JOLIETTE, MARSEILLE 2e&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TRAMES</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/2018-04-10_trames/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/2018-04-10_trames/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;# TRAMES&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//player.vimeo.com/video/191830797&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;À la Fondation Vasarely à Aix-en-Provence, Etienne Rey a choisi d’installer dans la salle des Intégrations architectoniques un ballet visuel hypnotique.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;«Trame instabilité» est un travail en cours de recherche. Le projet est basé sur des principes d’occultations partielles en couches associées à des trames qui font émerger une dimension immatérielle. L’expérience de perception de ces motifs produit un sentiment de basculement de la perception dans le sens où le motifs réel passe au second plan pour laisser place à l’émergence d’une figure du vide, c’est dans les blancs immatériel que des formes apparaissent et vacillent occupant tout notre champ visuel. Ces apparitions virtuelles, purs phénomènes optiques n’existent pas dans notre monde «physique», réel. &amp;lt;&lt;BR&gt;&amp;gt; Ce qui est en jeu ici c’est l’émergence de l’apparition de motifs virtuels résultat de la relation entre une réalité physique, la grandeur et l’ordonnancement de trames et notre physiologie qui conduit à cette état de perception. Lorsqu’on est fasse à ces motifs ce qui saute au yeux plus que le motif réel c’est sa résultante, instable et éphémère qui fait apparaitre une richesse de figures géométriques qui se transforment et évoluent en fonction du temps d’observation et du point de vue. Sur ce principe de dispositif optique, le travail de chacun des motifs, lié à un séquençage de trames conduit à faire apparaitre une composition et des émergences de formes spécifiques. L’expérience de perception de chacun des motifs explore les notions d’instabilité, de flux, d’émergences … dont l’expérience donne à entrevoir des formes que l’on retrouve dans la nature ou les phénomènes naturels: le dessin du pelage d’un zèbre, une accumulation de bulles de savons, ou plus généralement dans les compositions chimiques issue de la théorie de la morphogénèse de Turing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;featured.png&#34; alt=&#34;Sortie modèle&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;En collaboration avec le chercheur Laurent Perrinet, CNRS-AMU / Institut de Neurosciences de la Timone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trame, Élasticité &amp;amp; Écran n°3  étaient aussi présentés au Festival Ososphère, Strasbourg en Avril 2017.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TROPIQUE</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/2013-10-10_tropique/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/2013-10-10_tropique/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;tropique&#34;&gt;TROPIQUE&lt;/h1&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//player.vimeo.com/video/66161665&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/NaturalPatterns/Tropique&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://github.com/NaturalPatterns/Tropique&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.ran-dan.net/eng/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/E-REY-TropiqueS2-G-1024x576.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Sortie modèle&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.ososphere.org/catalogue/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/tropique_rey_oso2012_groslier8_Web_nb.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Tropique d&#39;Etienne Rey La Coop 2012 / Crédits photo Philippe Groslier&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Etienne Rey investigates the invisible and mutual relationships which take place between human and his environment. &lt;a href=&#34;http://digitalperformanceculture.blog.fr/2012/02/18/tropique-d-etienne-rey-12817804/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Prize-winner of the 1st call for projects of the RAN&lt;/a&gt;, its project of immersive installation Tropique puts in link the perception of the space connected to the movement, to the light and to the sound. Within the framework of a residence of creation in the Centre des arts, the object of which is ” to sculpt the light “, he presents a work in progress of this installation.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ondesparalleles.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/tropique_fiche_b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Tropique&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ondesparalleles.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/tropique_fiche_a.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Tropique&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ondesparalleles.org/projets/tropique-7/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Tropique&lt;/a&gt; est une installation environnementale, un espace vide de matière, qui se densiﬁe en ondes sonores et lumineuses, activées et modulées par la présence et l’activité humaines. Ce projet met en lien la perception de l’espace articulée au mouvement, à la lumière et au son. Les personnes qui se situent dans l’espace sont entourées d’une aura lumineuse et sonore qui ﬂuctue en fonction des mouvements et de la proximité des corps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ondesparalleles.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/tropique_fiche_c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Tropique&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Etienne Rey investigates the invisible and mutual relationships which take place between human and his environment. Prize-winner of the 1st call for projects of the RAN, its project of immersive installation Tropique puts in link the perception of the space connected to the movement, to the light and to the sound. Within the framework of a residence of creation in the Centre des arts, the object of which is ” to sculpt the light “, he presents a work in progress of this installation.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//player.vimeo.com/video/33718945&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ondesparalleles.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/tropique_fiche_d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Tropique&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ondesparalleles.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/tropique_fiche_l.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Tropique&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Tropique plonge le visiteur au coeur d’un espace embrumé, sculpté par la lumière et le son. Expérience sensorielle, le monde de Tropique évolue dans un entre-deux, rendant palpables des matérialités d’ordinaires invisibles. Expérience perceptive, le dispositif irradie l’espace, l’incorpore, l’amalgame, le dilate. La lumière se diffuse jusqu’à modifier notre rapport à l’espace, elle le redessine à travers notre propre vision et provoque une expérience personnelle, une émotion visuelle. L’environnement réagit aux variations de l’activité dans l’installation, à la façon dont nous l’habitons et le transformons. Tropique contruit un espace dynamique une architecture mobile à l’état de l’air, en miroir à notre présence. Ce qui est révélé est un ensemble vivant, la plupart du temps imperceptible, comme une mise une lumière de notre écosystème et de ses interrelations. Ce projet est élaboré avec le concours d’une équipe pluridisciplinaire composée d’un chercheur en Neuroscience : Laurent Perrinet, d’un compositeur : Wilfried Wendling d’un ingénieur : Julien Marro Dauzat.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;affiche_TROPIQUE-INT.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Tropique ß @ INT&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Accueilli en résidence dans le cadre des résidences de recherche de l’IMéRA pendant 6 mois (3 périodes de 2 mois),et soutenu dans le cadre d&amp;rsquo;un Atelier de l&amp;rsquo;!EuroMéditerranée, ce projet est élaboré en collaboration avec des chercheurs. Nous abordons ainsi les questions de la cognition et de la perception de l’espace liées à la vue, à l’audition, et au déplacement, auxquelles nous lierons les questions relatives à la diffusion de phénomènes ondulatoires.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;news&#34;&gt;news&lt;/h2&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//player.vimeo.com/video/56198653&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ondesparalleles.org/projets/space-odyssey/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;space odyssée&lt;/a&gt; à &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.institutfrancais-seoul.com/portfolio-item/exposition-home-cinema/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;l&amp;rsquo;institut francais en Coree du Sud de juin a octobre 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Un entretien d&amp;rsquo;ER durant le &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lA2bovigzLg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Mois multi 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Un entretien avec &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/z8328z2WO-w&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Roger Malina&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/z8328z2WO-w&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Installation &lt;a href=&#34;http://ondesparalleles.org/projets/space-odyssey/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Space Odyssey&lt;/a&gt; : Tournée en Corée avec Mac de Créteil en 2016 / dates et lieux à venir.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Installation &lt;a href=&#34;http://ondesparalleles.org/projets/space-odyssey/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Space Odyssey&lt;/a&gt; : FESTIVAL VIA / MAUBEUGE / 12 AU 22 MARS 2015 - FESTIVAL EXIT / CRÉTEIL / 26 MARS AU 05 AVRIL 2015 - LE PRINTEMPS À SAINT SAUVEUR / LILLE / 27 AVRIL 2016 AU 28 AOÛT 2016 : &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.maccreteil.com/fr/mac/event/338/Home-cinema-Festival-Exit#sthash.bEyRuaDX.dpuf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Home Cinema&lt;/a&gt;. À lire, sur &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.digitalarti.com/fr/blog/digitalarti_mag/home_cinema_matiere_audiovisuelle_modulable_pour_hyper_spectateur&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;digitatarti&lt;/a&gt;.
Installation &lt;a href=&#34;http://ondesparalleles.org/projets/tropique-7/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Tropique&lt;/a&gt; : Festival international d’arts multidisciplinaires et électroniques &lt;a href=&#34;http://mmrectoverso.org/fr/mois-multi/spectacles/installations-2/tropique/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Le Mois Multi 16 / Québec du 4 février au 1 mars 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Installation &lt;a href=&#34;http://ondesparalleles.org/projets/space-odyssey/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Space Odyssey&lt;/a&gt; : Lille 3000, du 26 SEPT 2015 &amp;gt; 17 JAN 2016&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Installation &lt;a href=&#34;http://ondesparalleles.org/projets/space-odyssey/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Space Odyssey&lt;/a&gt; : FESTIVAL INTERNATIONAL EXIT 2015 Créteil du 26 MARS -&amp;gt; 05 AVRIL 2015&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Installation &lt;a href=&#34;http://ondesparalleles.org/projets/space-odyssey/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Space Odyssey&lt;/a&gt; : Festival Via 2015, Maubeuge du jeudi 12 mars 2015 au dimanche 22 mars 2015&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Du 13 au 23 Mars 2014: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lemanege.com/cgi?lg=fr&amp;amp;pag=1310&amp;amp;tab=108&amp;amp;rec=1188&amp;amp;frm=0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;TROPIQUE @ FESTIVAL VIA&lt;/a&gt; : Depuis presque 30 ans, le Festival VIA flirte avec les frontières des territoires artistiques, à la croisée des arts de la scène, de la création technologique et numérique. Toujours plus international et interdisciplinaire, VIA traduit, à Maubeuge et à Mons, la vitalité de la scène contemporaine. Il est également à noter que cette édition préfigure la Capitale européenne de la culture 2015 qui se déroulera dans ces deux villes l&amp;rsquo;année prochaine.  Pour cette nouvelle édition de VIA sera présentée l&amp;rsquo;installation Tropique d&amp;rsquo;Étienne Rey, produite par Seconde Nature et récemment dévoilée lors du festival « Chroniques des Mondes Possibles » dans le cadre d&amp;rsquo;E-topie, Marseille-Provence 2013.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;16 novembre au 15 décembre 2013: présentation à Paris dans le cadre du festival &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.digitalarti.com/fr/blog/digitalarti_mag/festival_nemo_tropiques_etienne_rey&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;nemo&lt;/a&gt; ; écouter &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.franceinter.fr/emission-latac-faux-sourires-vision-cosmique-installation-tropique&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;la tête au carré sur France Inter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10 Octobre au 10 novembre 2013: présentation finale à la fondation Vasarely à Aix-en-Provence dans le cadre du festival &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fondationvasarely.org/uk/e_topie.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;e-Topie&lt;/a&gt;, cf &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.liberation.fr/culture/2013/10/15/riche-e-topie-a-aix_939736&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;cahier beaux-arts de libé&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.laprovence.com/article/economie/2628580/aix-la-ville-candidate-pour-devenir-quartier-numerique.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;la provence&lt;/a&gt;  : 10450 spectateurs sur 32 jours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Juin 2013: &lt;a href=&#34;http://invibe.net/LaurentPerrinet/EtienneRey?action=AttachFile&amp;amp;do=get&amp;amp;target=affiche_TROPIQUE-INT.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;résidence à l&amp;rsquo;INT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Décembre 2012: dans le &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mp2013.fr/evenements/2013/10/atelier-de-leuromediterranee-tropique-etienne-rey-a-limera/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;programme officiel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Décembre 2012: signature de la convention avec le CNRS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tropique est présenté &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ososphere.org/2012/evenement/tropique/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;07 au 14 décembre 2012, dans le cadre du festival &amp;ldquo;Les nuits de l’Ososphère&amp;rdquo; de Strasbourg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Juin 2012: Tropique en résidence à la fondation Vasarely&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mars 2012: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mecenesdusud.fr/blog/index.php?post/2012/03/Tropique-%C3%A0-Nantes&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Tropique à Nantes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://creative.arte.tv/en/space/Tropique/messages/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Arte creative&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tropique @ &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ran-dan.net/eng/?p=22&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;RAN (Enghien-les-Bains)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/33718945&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Etienne Rey Tropique Experimentation Film2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turbulences</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/2018-01-20_turbulences/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/2018-01-20_turbulences/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;turbulences&#34;&gt;Turbulences&lt;/h1&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//player.vimeo.com/video/303255760&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;h2 id=&#34;installation-in-situ-2018-collection-of-the-françois-schneider-foundation-wattwiller-i-2018&#34;&gt;Installation in situ, 2018; Collection of the François Schneider Foundation, Wattwiller I 2018&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;En agissant sur les variations et les rayonnements d’ordre physique, Etienne Rey fait apparaître l’épaisseur existentielle du vide.&amp;rdquo; Bénédicte Chevallier, Mécènes du Sud&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;L’installation Turbulences explore l’émergence de caustiques, phénomènes caractéristiques de la relation entre l’eau, la lumière et l’air.
Le mouvement y perturbe un état optique stable. La turbulence des plis lumineux donne l’illusion d’un corps flottant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Installation immersive plastique et sonore, l’expérience de l’oeuvre se joue dans l’exploration de dimensions immatérielles par l’observateur.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Création originale pour la Fondation François Schneider
Production : Quatre 4.0 / L’Ososphère, en partenariat avec la Fondation François Schneider et le soutien de la Région Grand Est
Accompagnement, production déléguée : bOssa&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;INAUGURATION : SAMEDI 27 OCTOBRE 2018&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;EXPOSITION &amp;gt; 20 JANVIER 2019&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FONDATION FRANÇOIS SCHNEIDER - 27 RUE DE LA PREMIÈRE ARMÉE, 68700 WATTWILLER&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
