<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>eye movements | Novel visual computations</title>
    <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/tags/eye-movements/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://laurentperrinet.github.io/tags/eye-movements/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>eye movements</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>This material is presented to ensure timely dissemination of scholarly and technical work. Copyright and all rights therein are retained by authors or by other copyright holders. All persons copying this information are expected to adhere to the terms and constraints invoked by each author&#39;s copyright. In most cases, these works may not be reposted without the explicit permission of the copyright holder. 
This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 3.0 Unported License Please note that multiple distribution, publication or commercial usage of copyrighted papers included in this website would require submission of a permission request addressed to the journal in which the paper appeared. </copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/img/hulk.png</url>
      <title>eye movements</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/tags/eye-movements/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reinforcement effects in anticipatory smooth eye movements</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/damasse-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/damasse-18/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic modulation of volatility by reward contingencies: effects on anticipatory smooth eye movement</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/damasse-17-vss/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/damasse-17-vss/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the dynamics of human smooth pursuit is influenced by speed uncertainty</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/mansour-17-ecvp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/mansour-17-ecvp/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Voluntary tracking the moving clouds : Effects of speed variability on human smooth pursuit</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/mansour-17-gdr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/mansour-17-gdr/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Operant reinforcement versus reward expectancy: effects on anticipatory eye movements</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/damasse-16-vss/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/damasse-16-vss/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effects of motion predictability on anticipatory and visually-guided eye movements: a common prior for sensory processing and motor control?</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/montagnini-16-ecvp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/montagnini-16-ecvp/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modeling the effect of dynamic contingencies on anticipatory eye movements</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/damasse-16-ecvp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/damasse-16-ecvp/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Voluntary tracking the moving clouds : Effects of speed variability on human smooth pursuit</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/mansour-16-ecvp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/mansour-16-ecvp/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Voluntary tracking the moving clouds : Effects of speed variability on human smooth pursuit</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/mansour-16-gdr/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/mansour-16-gdr/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Voluntary tracking the moving clouds : Effects of speed variability on human smooth pursuit</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/mansour-16-sfn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/mansour-16-sfn/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anticipatory smooth eye movements and reinforcement</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/damasse-15-vss/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/damasse-15-vss/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anticipatory smooth eye movements as operant behavior</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/damasse-15-gdr/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/damasse-15-gdr/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Active inference, eye movements and oculomotor delays</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/perrinet-adams-friston-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/perrinet-adams-friston-14/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;active-inference-tracking-eye-movements-and-oculomotor-delays&#34;&gt;Active Inference, tracking eye movements and oculomotor delays&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tracking eye movements face a difficult task: they have to be fast while they suffer inevitable delays. If we focus on area MT of humans for instance as it is crucial for detecting the motion of visual objects, sensory information coming to this area is already lagging some 35 milliseconds behind operational time – that is, it reflects some past information. Still the fastest action that may be done there is only able to reach the effector muscles of the eyes some 40 milliseconds later – that is, in the future. The tracking eye movement system is however able to respond swiftly and even to anticipate repetitive movements (e.g. Barnes et al, 2000 – refs in manuscript). In that case, it means that information in a cortical area is both predicted from the past sensory information but also anticipated to give an optimal response in the future. Even if numerous models have been described to model different mechanisms to account for delays, no theoretical approach has tackled the whole problem explicitly. In several areas of vision research, authors have proposed models at different levels of abstractions from biomechanical models, to neurobiological implementations (e.g. Robinson, 1986) or Bayesian models. This study is both novel and important because – using a neurobiologically plausible hierarchical Bayesian model – it demonstrates that using generalized coordinates to finesse the prediction of a target&amp;rsquo;s motion, the model can reproduce characteristic properties of tracking eye movements in the presence of delays. Crucially, the different refinements to the model that we propose – pursuit initiation, smooth pursuit eye movements, and anticipatory response – are consistent with the different types of tracking eye movements that may be observed experimentally.






&lt;figure&gt;

  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;featured.png&#34; &gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;featured.png&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; &gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(A)&lt;/strong&gt; This figure reports the response of predictive processing during the simulation of pursuit initiation, using a single sweep of a visual target, while compensating for sensory motor delays. Here, we see horizontal excursions of oculomotor angle (red line). One can see clearly the initial displacement of the target that is suppressed by action after a few hundred milliseconds. Additionally, we illustrate the effects of assuming wrong sensorimotor delays on pursuit initiation. Under pure sensory delays (blue dotted line), one can see clearly the delay in sensory predictions, in relation to the true inputs. With pure motor delays (blue dashed line) and with combined sensorimotor delays (blue line) there is a failure of optimal control with oscillatory fluctuations in oculomotor trajectories, which may become unstable. &lt;strong&gt;(B)&lt;/strong&gt; This figure reports the simulation of smooth pursuit when the target motion is hemi-sinusoidal, as would happen for a pendulum that would be stopped at each half cycle left of the vertical (broken black lines in the lower-right panel). We report the horizontal excursions of oculomotor angle. The generative model used here has been equipped with a second hierarchical level that contains hidden states, modeling latent periodic behavior of the (hidden) causes of target motion. With this addition, the improvement in pursuit accuracy apparent at the onset of the second cycle of motion is observed (pink shaded area), similar to psychophysical experimentss.&lt;/h4&gt;
  
&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The characteristics of microsaccadic eye movements varied with the change of strategy in a match-to-sample task</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/simoncini-14-vss/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/simoncini-14-vss/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Axonal delays and on-time control of eye movements</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/talk/2014-01-10-int-fest/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/talk/2014-01-10-int-fest/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the nature of anticipatory eye movements and the factors affecting them</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/damasse-14-gdr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/damasse-14-gdr/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measuring speed of moving textures: Different pooling of motion information for human ocular following and perception</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/simoncini-13-vss/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/simoncini-13-vss/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smooth Pursuit and Visual Occlusion: Active Inference and Oculomotor Control in Schizophrenia</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/adams-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/adams-12/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The behavioral receptive field underlying motion integration for primate tracking eye movements</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/masson-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/masson-12/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grabbing, tracking and sniffing as models for motion detection and eye movements</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/talk/2012-01-27-fil/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/talk/2012-01-27-fil/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motion-based prediction is sufficient to solve the aperture problem</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/talk/2012-01-12-vision-at-ucl/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2012 17:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/talk/2012-01-12-vision-at-ucl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;See a followup in &lt;a href=&#34;https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/perrinet-12-pred/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Perrinet et al, 2012&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effect of image statistics on fixational eye movements</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/simoncini-12-vss/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/simoncini-12-vss/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measuring speed of moving textures: Different pooling of motion information for human ocular following and perception.</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/simoncini-12-coding/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/simoncini-12-coding/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More is not always better: dissociation between perception and action explained by adaptive gain control</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/simoncini-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/simoncini-12/</guid>
      <description>





&lt;figure&gt;

  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;grating.gif&#34; &gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;grating.gif&#34; width=&#34;80%&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; &gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;&lt;em&gt;Band-pass motion stimuli for perception and action tasks.&lt;/em&gt; (a) In the space representing temporal against spatial frequency, each line going through the origin corresponds to stimuli moving at the same speed. A simple drifting grating is a single point in this space. Our moving texture stimuli had their energy distributed within an ellipse elongated along a given speed line, keeping constant the mean spatial and temporal frequencies. The spatio-temporal bandwidth was manipulated by co-varying Bsf and Btf as illustrated by the (x,y,t) examples. Human performance was measured for two different tasks, run in parallel blocks. (b) For ocular tracking, motion stimuli were presented for a short duration (200ms) in the wake of a centering saccade to control both attention and fixation states. &amp;copy; For speed discrimination, test and reference stimuli were presented successively for the same duration and subjects were instructed to indicate whether the test stimulus was perceived as slower or faster than reference.&lt;/h4&gt;
  
&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pattern discrimination for moving random textures: Richer stimuli are more difficult to recognize</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/simoncini-11-vss/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/simoncini-11-vss/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perceptions as Hypotheses: Saccades as Experiments</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/friston-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/friston-12/</guid>
      <description>





&lt;figure&gt;

  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://www.frontiersin.org/files/Articles/21922/fpsyg-03-00151-r4/image_m/fpsyg-03-00151-g001.jpg&#34; &gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.frontiersin.org/files/Articles/21922/fpsyg-03-00151-r4/image_m/fpsyg-03-00151-g001.jpg&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; &gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This schematic shows the dependencies among various quantities that are assumed when modeling the exchanges of a self organizing system like the brain with the environment.&lt;/strong&gt; The top panel describes the states of the environment and the system or agent in terms of a probabilistic dependency graph, where connections denote directed dependencies. The quantities are described within the nodes of this graph with exemplar forms for their dependencies on other variables (see main text). Here, hidden and internal states are separated by action and sensory states. Both action and internal states encoding a conditional density minimize free energy, while internal states encoding prior beliefs maximize salience. Both free energy and salience are defined in terms of a generative model that is shown as fictive dependency graph in the lower panel. Note that the variables in the real world and the form of their dynamics are different from that assumed by the generative model; this is why external states are in bold. Furthermore, note that action is a state in the model of the brain but is replaced by hidden controls in the brain’s model of its world. This means that the agent is not aware of action but has beliefs about hidden causes in the world that action can fulfill through minimizing free energy. These beliefs correspond to prior expectations that sensory states will be sampled in a way that optimizes conditional confidence or salience.&lt;/h4&gt;
  
&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pattern discrimination for moving random textures: Richer stimuli are more difficult to recognize</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/simoncini-2011-pattern/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/simoncini-2011-pattern/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Propriétés émergentes d&#39;un modèle de prédiction probabiliste utilisant un champ neural</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/talk/2011-07-02-neuro-med-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/talk/2011-07-02-neuro-med-talk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;La finalité de cette manifestation est de permettre à nos chercheurs de se réunir en groupes de travail et en ateliers afin de découvrir la thématique des neurosciences et son interdisciplinarité. La manifestation se tient dans le cadre des activités du laboratoire LAMS, de ABC MATHINFO, du GDRI NeurO et du réseau méditerranéen &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.neuromedproject.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;NeuroMed&lt;/a&gt;.
* related publication @ &lt;a href=&#34;https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/khoei-10-tauc/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;SPIE 2008&lt;/a&gt;
* see this more recent talk @ &lt;a href=&#34;https://laurentperrinet.github.io/talk/2012-01-12-vision-at-ucl/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;UCL, London&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saccadic foveation of a moving visual target in the rhesus monkey</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/fleuriet-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/fleuriet-11/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probabilistic models of the low-level visual system: the role of prediction in detecting motion</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/talk/2010-12-17-tauc-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/talk/2010-12-17-tauc-talk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An event ranging &amp;ldquo;From Mathematical Image Analysis to Neurogeometry of the Brain&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.conftauc.cnrs-gif.fr/programme.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;LADISLAV TAUC &amp;amp; GDR MSPC NEUROSCIENCES CONFERENCE&lt;/a&gt;.
* related publication from Mina Khoei @ &lt;a href=&#34;https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/khoei-10-tauc/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;TAUC 2012&lt;/a&gt;
* see this more recent talk @ &lt;a href=&#34;https://laurentperrinet.github.io/talk/2012-01-12-vision-at-ucl/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;UCL, London&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Role of homeostasis in learning sparse representations</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/perrinet-10-shl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/perrinet-10-shl/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Models of low-level vision: linking probabilistic models and neural masses</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/talk/2010-01-08-facets/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/talk/2010-01-08-facets/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;see this more recent talk @ &lt;a href=&#34;https://laurentperrinet.github.io/talk/2012-01-12-vision-at-ucl/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;UCL, London&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Different pooling of motion information for perceptual speed discrimination and behavioral speed estimation</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/simoncini-10-vss/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/simoncini-10-vss/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamical emergence of a neural solution for motion integration</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/perrinet-10-areadne/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/perrinet-10-areadne/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probabilistic models of the low-level visual system: the role of prediction in detecting motion</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/perrinet-10-tauc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/perrinet-10-tauc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;See a followup in &lt;a href=&#34;https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/perrinet-12-pred/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Perrinet et al, 2012&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decoding center-surround interactions in population of neurons for the ocular following response</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/perrinet-09-cosyne/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/perrinet-09-cosyne/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamics of distributed 1D and 2D motion representations for short-latency ocular following</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/barthelemy-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/barthelemy-08/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decoding the population dynamics underlying ocular following response using a probabilistic framework</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/perrinet-08-areadne/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/perrinet-08-areadne/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modeling spatial integration in the ocular following response to center-surround stimulation using a probabilistic framework</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/perrinet-08-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/perrinet-08-a/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamical Neural Networks: modeling low-level vision at short latencies</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/perrinet-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/perrinet-07/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dynamical Neural Networks (DyNNs) are a class of models for networks of neurons where particular focus is put on the role of time in the emergence of functional computational properties. The definition and study of these models involves the cooperation of a large range of scientific fields from statistical physics, probabilistic modelling, neuroscience and psychology to control theory. It focuses on the mechanisms that may be relevant for studying cognition by hypothesizing that information is distributed in the activity of the neurons in the system and that the timing helps in maintaining this information to lastly form decisions or actions. The system responds at best to the constraints of the outside world and learning strategies tune this internal dynamics to achieve optimal performance.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modeling spatial integration in the ocular following response using a probabilistic framework</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/perrinet-07-neurocomp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/perrinet-07-neurocomp/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Input-output transformation in the visuo-oculomotor loop: modeling the ocular following response to center-surround stimulation in a probabilistic framework</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/perrinet-06-neurocomp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/perrinet-06-neurocomp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;See a followup in &lt;a href=&#34;https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/perrinet-12-pred/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Perrinet et al, 2012&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
