<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Stéphane Viollet | Novel visual computations</title>
    <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/author/stephane-viollet/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://laurentperrinet.github.io/author/stephane-viollet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Stéphane Viollet</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>This material is presented to ensure timely dissemination of scholarly and technical work. Copyright and all rights therein are retained by authors or by other copyright holders. All persons copying this information are expected to adhere to the terms and constraints invoked by each author&#39;s copyright. In most cases, these works may not be reposted without the explicit permission of the copyright holder. 
This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 3.0 Unported License Please note that multiple distribution, publication or commercial usage of copyrighted papers included in this website would require submission of a permission request addressed to the journal in which the paper appeared. </copyright>
    <image>
      <url>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/media/hulk.png</url>
      <title>Stéphane Viollet</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/author/stephane-viollet/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>ANR AgileNeuroBot (2021/2024)</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/grant/anr-anb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/grant/anr-anb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Type de contrat : Subvention / Aide&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coordinateur Scientifique : PERRINET Laurent (UMR7289)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Durée: 3 ans, à partir du 1er avril 2021&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Budget total: 435 k€ , bugdget INT: 170 k€&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Partenaire(s) : AGENCE NATIONALE DE LA RECHERCHE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Responsable Scientifique INT : PERRINET Laurent (UMR7289)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;résumé&#34;&gt;Résumé&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Des robots aériens autonomes seraient des outils essentiels dans les opérations de recherche et de sauvetage. Toutefois, voler dans des environnements complexes exige un haut niveau d&amp;rsquo;agilité, ce qui implique par exemple la capacité de déclencher des manœuvres agressives pour esquiver les obstacles: Les caméras et algorithmes d&amp;rsquo;intelligence artificielle conventionnels n&amp;rsquo;ont pas ces capacités. Dans ce projet, nous proposerons une solution associant de manière bio-inspirée une dynamique rapide de détection visuelle et de stabilisation. Nous intégrerons ces différents aspects dans un système neuromorphique événementiel de bout en bout. La clé de cette approche est l&amp;rsquo;optimisation des délais du système par traitement prédictif. Ceci permettra de voler indépendamment, sans aucune intervention de l&amp;rsquo;utilisateur. Notre objectif à plus long terme est de satisfaire ces besoins avec un minimum d&amp;rsquo;énergie et de fournir des solutions novatrices aux défis des algorithmes traditionnels d&amp;rsquo;IA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autonomous aerial robots would be essential tools in search and rescue operations. But flying in complex environments requires a high level of agility, which implies the ability to initiate aggressive maneuvers to avoid obstacles: Conventional AI cameras and algorithms do not have these capabilities. In this project, we propose a solution that will integrate bio-inspired rapid visual detection and stabilization dynamics into an end-to-end event based neuromorphic system. The key to this approach will be the optimization of delays through predictive processing. This will allow these robots to fly independently, without any user intervention. Our longer-term goal is to meet the requirements with very little power and provide innovative solutions to the challenges of traditional AI algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;acknowledgement&#34;&gt;Acknowledgement&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work was supported by ANR project &amp;ldquo;AgileNeuroBot&amp;rdquo; N° ANR-XX-XXX-XXXX.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>M2APix: a bio-inspired auto-adaptive visual sensor for robust ground height estimation</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/dupeyroux-boutin-serres-perrinet-viollet-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/dupeyroux-boutin-serres-perrinet-viollet-18/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
