<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Novel visual computations</title>
    <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/authors/rick-a.-adams/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://laurentperrinet.github.io/authors/rick-a.-adams/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Novel visual computations</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>This material is presented to ensure timely dissemination of scholarly and technical work. Copyright and all rights therein are retained by authors or by other copyright holders. All persons copying this information are expected to adhere to the terms and constraints invoked by each author&#39;s copyright. In most cases, these works may not be reposted without the explicit permission of the copyright holder. 
This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 3.0 Unported License Please note that multiple distribution, publication or commercial usage of copyrighted papers included in this website would require submission of a permission request addressed to the journal in which the paper appeared. </copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/img/hulk.png</url>
      <title>Novel visual computations</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/authors/rick-a.-adams/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compensation of oculomotor delays in the visual system&#39;s network</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/perrinet-16-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/perrinet-16-networks/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Active inference, eye movements and oculomotor delays</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/perrinet-adams-friston-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/perrinet-adams-friston-14/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;active-inference-tracking-eye-movements-and-oculomotor-delays&#34;&gt;Active Inference, tracking eye movements and oculomotor delays&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tracking eye movements face a difficult task: they have to be fast while they suffer inevitable delays. If we focus on area MT of humans for instance as it is crucial for detecting the motion of visual objects, sensory information coming to this area is already lagging some 35 milliseconds behind operational time – that is, it reflects some past information. Still the fastest action that may be done there is only able to reach the effector muscles of the eyes some 40 milliseconds later – that is, in the future. The tracking eye movement system is however able to respond swiftly and even to anticipate repetitive movements (e.g. Barnes et al, 2000 – refs in manuscript). In that case, it means that information in a cortical area is both predicted from the past sensory information but also anticipated to give an optimal response in the future. Even if numerous models have been described to model different mechanisms to account for delays, no theoretical approach has tackled the whole problem explicitly. In several areas of vision research, authors have proposed models at different levels of abstractions from biomechanical models, to neurobiological implementations (e.g. Robinson, 1986) or Bayesian models. This study is both novel and important because – using a neurobiologically plausible hierarchical Bayesian model – it demonstrates that using generalized coordinates to finesse the prediction of a target&amp;rsquo;s motion, the model can reproduce characteristic properties of tracking eye movements in the presence of delays. Crucially, the different refinements to the model that we propose – pursuit initiation, smooth pursuit eye movements, and anticipatory response – are consistent with the different types of tracking eye movements that may be observed experimentally.






&lt;figure&gt;

  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;featured.png&#34; &gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;featured.png&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; &gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(A)&lt;/strong&gt; This figure reports the response of predictive processing during the simulation of pursuit initiation, using a single sweep of a visual target, while compensating for sensory motor delays. Here, we see horizontal excursions of oculomotor angle (red line). One can see clearly the initial displacement of the target that is suppressed by action after a few hundred milliseconds. Additionally, we illustrate the effects of assuming wrong sensorimotor delays on pursuit initiation. Under pure sensory delays (blue dotted line), one can see clearly the delay in sensory predictions, in relation to the true inputs. With pure motor delays (blue dashed line) and with combined sensorimotor delays (blue line) there is a failure of optimal control with oscillatory fluctuations in oculomotor trajectories, which may become unstable. &lt;strong&gt;(B)&lt;/strong&gt; This figure reports the simulation of smooth pursuit when the target motion is hemi-sinusoidal, as would happen for a pendulum that would be stopped at each half cycle left of the vertical (broken black lines in the lower-right panel). We report the horizontal excursions of oculomotor angle. The generative model used here has been equipped with a second hierarchical level that contains hidden states, modeling latent periodic behavior of the (hidden) causes of target motion. With this addition, the improvement in pursuit accuracy apparent at the onset of the second cycle of motion is observed (pink shaded area), similar to psychophysical experimentss.&lt;/h4&gt;
  
&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Active inference, eye movements and oculomotor delays</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/perrinet-13-cns/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/perrinet-13-cns/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Active inference, eye movements and oculomotor delays</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/perrinet-13-jffos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/perrinet-13-jffos/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smooth Pursuit and Visual Occlusion: Active Inference and Oculomotor Control in Schizophrenia</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/adams-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/adams-12/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Active inference, smooth pursuit and oculomotor delays</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/perrinet-12-areadne/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/perrinet-12-areadne/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perceptions as Hypotheses: Saccades as Experiments</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/friston-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/friston-12/</guid>
      <description>





&lt;figure&gt;

  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://www.frontiersin.org/files/Articles/21922/fpsyg-03-00151-r4/image_m/fpsyg-03-00151-g001.jpg&#34; &gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.frontiersin.org/files/Articles/21922/fpsyg-03-00151-r4/image_m/fpsyg-03-00151-g001.jpg&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; &gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This schematic shows the dependencies among various quantities that are assumed when modeling the exchanges of a self organizing system like the brain with the environment.&lt;/strong&gt; The top panel describes the states of the environment and the system or agent in terms of a probabilistic dependency graph, where connections denote directed dependencies. The quantities are described within the nodes of this graph with exemplar forms for their dependencies on other variables (see main text). Here, hidden and internal states are separated by action and sensory states. Both action and internal states encoding a conditional density minimize free energy, while internal states encoding prior beliefs maximize salience. Both free energy and salience are defined in terms of a generative model that is shown as fictive dependency graph in the lower panel. Note that the variables in the real world and the form of their dynamics are different from that assumed by the generative model; this is why external states are in bold. Furthermore, note that action is a state in the model of the brain but is replaced by hidden controls in the brain’s model of its world. This means that the agent is not aware of action but has beliefs about hidden causes in the world that action can fulfill through minimizing free energy. These beliefs correspond to prior expectations that sensory states will be sampled in a way that optimizes conditional confidence or salience.&lt;/h4&gt;
  
&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
