<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Matthias S. Keil on Novel visual computations</title>
    <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/authors/matthias-s.-keil/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Matthias S. Keil on Novel visual computations</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This material is presented to ensure timely dissemination of scholarly and technical work. Copyright and all rights therein are retained by authors or by other copyright holders. All persons copying this information are expected to adhere to the terms and constraints invoked by each author&#39;s copyright. In most cases, these works may not be reposted without the explicit permission of the copyright holder.
&lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Creative Commons License&#34; style=&#34;border-width:0&#34; src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/3.0/88x31.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This work is licensed under a &lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 3.0 Unported License&lt;/a&gt;
Please note that multiple distribution, publication or commercial usage of copyrighted papers included in this website would require submission of a permission request addressed to the journal in which the paper appeared.
</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://laurentperrinet.github.io/authors/matthias-s.-keil/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/cristobal-perrinet-keil-15-bicv-chap-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/cristobal-perrinet-keil-15-bicv-chap-1/</guid>
      <description>  Mindmap of the book contents. Cross-links between chapters have been indicated as thin lines.   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biologically Inspired Computer Vision</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/cristobal-perrinet-keil-15-bicv/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/cristobal-perrinet-keil-15-bicv/</guid>
      <description>Biologically Inspired Computer vision   Biologically Inspired Computer Vision As state-of-the-art imaging technologies becomes more and more advanced, yielding scientific data at unprecedented detail and volume, the need to process and interpret all the data has made image processing and computer vision also increasingly important. Sources of data that have to be routinely dealt with today applications include video transmission, wireless communication, automatic fingerprint processing, massive databanks, non-weary and accurate automatic airport screening, robust night vision to name a few.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>