<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>grant on Novel computational paradigms for vision</title>
    <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/categories/grant/</link>
    <description>Recent content in grant on Novel computational paradigms for vision</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This material is presented to ensure timely dissemination of scholarly and technical work. Copyright and all rights therein are retained by authors or by other copyright holders. All persons copying this information are expected to adhere to the terms and constraints invoked by each author&#39;s copyright. In most cases, these works may not be reposted without the explicit permission of the copyright holder.
&lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Creative Commons License&#34; style=&#34;border-width:0&#34; src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/3.0/88x31.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This work is licensed under a &lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 3.0 Unported License&lt;/a&gt;
Please note that multiple distribution, publication or commercial usage of copyrighted papers included in this website would require submission of a permission request addressed to the journal in which the paper appeared.
</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://laurentperrinet.github.io/categories/grant/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>ANR BalaV1 (2013/2016)</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/project/anr-bala-v1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/project/anr-bala-v1/</guid>
      <description>ANR BalaV1: Balanced states in area V1 (2013&amp;frasl;2016) In carnivores and primates the orientation selectivity (OS) of the cells in the primary visual cortex (V1) is organized in maps in which preferred orientations (POs) of the cells change gradually except near “pin- wheels”, around which all orientations are present. Over the last half-century the mechanism for OS has been hotly debated. However the theories that purport to explain OS have almost all considered cortical networks in which the neurons receive input preferentially from cells with similar PO.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ANR CausaL (2018/2022)</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/project/anr-causal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/project/anr-causal/</guid>
      <description>Humans have an extraordinary capacity to infer cause-effect relations. In particular, we excel in forming ​beliefs ​about the ​causal effect of actions​. Causal learning provides the basis for rational decision-making and allows people to engage in meaningful life and social interactions. Causal learning is a form of goal-directed learning, defined as the capacity to rapidly learn the consequence of actions and to select behaviours according to goals and motivational state. This ability is based on internal models of the consequence of our behaviors​ and relies on learning rules determined by the​ contingency between actions and outcomes​.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ANR Horizontal-V1 (2017/2021)</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/project/anr-horizontal-v1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/project/anr-horizontal-v1/</guid>
      <description>The Horizontal-V1 project aims at understanding the emergence of sensory predictions linking local shape attributes (orientation, contour) to global indices of movement (direction, speed, trajectory) at the earliest stage of cortical processing (primary visual cortex, i.e. V1). We will study how the long-distance &amp;ldquo;horizontal&amp;rdquo; connectivity, intrinsic to V1 and the feedback from higher cortical areas contribute to a dynamic processing of local-to-global features as a function of the context (eg displacement along a trajectory; during reafference change induced by eye-movements&amp;hellip;).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ANR PredictEye (2018/2022)</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/project/anr-predicteye/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/project/anr-predicteye/</guid>
      <description>The objectives of PREDICTEYE is to rigorously test and define the functional and neurophysiological grounds of probabilistic oculomotor internal models by investigating the multiple timescales at which the trajectory of a moving target is learned and represented in a probabilistic framework (Aim #1). Second, we will investigate the role of (pre)frontal oculomotor networks in building such probabilistic representations and their impact upon two of their downstream neural targets of the brainstem premotor centers (superior colliculus for saccades; NRTP for pursuit) (Aim #2).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ANR REM (2013/2016)</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/project/anr-rem/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/project/anr-rem/</guid>
      <description>http://static.tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pub/images/R.E.M..jpg
Reinforcement learning theory provides a general conceptual framework to account for behavioral changes. Recently the idea that reinforcement may be used to explain learning in motor responses has emerged. In particular, there is a growing interest in studying the effects of reinforcement learning in arm movements trajectories (Dam, Kording, &amp;amp; Wei, 2013), pointing movements (Trommershauser, Landy, &amp;amp; Maloney, 2006), or eye movements (Madelain, Champrenaut, &amp;amp; Chauvin, 2007; Madelain &amp;amp; Krauzlis, 2003b; Madelain, Paeye, &amp;amp; Wallman, 2011; Sugrue, Corrado, &amp;amp; Newsome, 2004; Takikawa, Kawagoe, Itoh, Nakahara, &amp;amp; Hikosaka, 2002; Xu-Wilson, Zee, &amp;amp; Shadmehr, 2009).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ANR SPEED (2013/2016)</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/project/anr-speed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/project/anr-speed/</guid>
      <description>Measuring speed and direction of moving objects is an essential computational step in order to move our eyes, hands or other body parts with respect to the environment. Whereas encoding and decoding of direction information is now largely understood in various neuronal systems, how the human brain accurately represents speed information remains largely unknown. Speed tuned neurons have been identified in several early cortical visual areas in monkeys. However, how such speed tuning emerges is not yet understood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ANR TRAJECTORY (2016/2019)</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/project/anr-trajectory/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/project/anr-trajectory/</guid>
      <description>Global motion processing is a major computational task of biological visual systems. When an object moves across the visual field, the sequence of visited positions is strongly correlated in space and time, forming a trajectory. These correlated images generate a sequence of local activation of the feed-forward stream. Local properties such as position, direction and orientation can be extracted at each time step by a feed-forward cascade of linear filters and static non-linearities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DOC2AMU (2016/2019)</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/project/doc-2-amu/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/project/doc-2-amu/</guid>
      <description>DOC2AMU is co-funded by the prestigious Marie Skłodowska-Curie COFUND action within the H2020 Research and Innovation programme of the European Union and by the Regional Council of Provence-Alpes-Côte d’Azur, with a contribution from A*MIDEX Foundation.
Within this programme, the PhD fellows will sign a three-year work contract with one of the 12 Doctoral Schools of AMU. Numerous advantages
These PhD fellowships are remunerated above that of a standard French PhD contract with a gross monthly salary of 2600 € and a gross monthly mobility allowance of 300 €, which after standard deductions will amount to a net salary of approximately 1625€/month (net amount may vary slightly).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhD ICN (2017 / 2021)</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/project/phd-icn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/project/phd-icn/</guid>
      <description>Description
The [Ph.D. program in Integrative and Clinical Neuroscience](http://neuro-marseille.org/en/phd-program-en/) (Aix-Marseille University) is offering in 2017 three Ph.D. scholarships to Master students graduated from highly ranked international universities (outside France). We were awarded with one PhD position for Angelo Franciosini at the &amp;quot;Institut de Neurosciences de la Timone&amp;quot; (team &amp;quot;Inference and Visual Behavior&amp;quot;), CNRS, Marseille (France) to study trajectories in natural images and the sensory processing of contours.  Funding
This project is funded by the Aix-Marseille Université, which was awarded the prestigious status of &amp;quot;Excellence Initiative&amp;quot; (A*MIDEX) by the French Government and considering interdisciplinary studies as one of its main axes of growth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ANR TRAJECTORY (2016/2019)</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/project/brain-scales/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/project/brain-scales/</guid>
      <description>Global motion processing is a major computational task of biological visual systems. When an object moves across the visual field, the sequence of visited positions is strongly correlated in space and time, forming a trajectory. These correlated images generate a sequence of local activation of the feed-forward stream. Local properties such as position, direction and orientation can be extracted at each time step by a feed-forward cascade of linear filters and static non-linearities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CODDE (2008/2012)</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/project/codde/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/project/codde/</guid>
      <description>The CODDE network studies the links between sensory input, brain activity and motor output. It does this by combining behavioural techniques, brain imaging, movement recording and computational modelling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FACETS (2006/2010)</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/project/facets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/project/facets/</guid>
      <description>List of publications that were funded by the FACETS project (more info).
 also available on the FACET&amp;rsquo;s website  See also:
 The FACETS research project which ended on 31 August 2010.
 The FACETS-ITN Marie-Curie initital training network for graduate training continues until August 2013
 The BrainScaleS project builds on and extends the research done in FACETS. This 4 year project started on 1 January 2011</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FACETS-ITN (2010/2013)</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/project/facets-itn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/project/facets-itn/</guid>
      <description>FACETS-ITN: From Neuroscience to neuro-inspired computing (2010&amp;frasl;2013) 
FACETS ITN project (EU funding, grant number 237955) is a &amp;lsquo;Marie-Curie Initial Training Network&amp;rsquo; involves 15 groups at European Research Universities, Research Centers and Industrial Partners in 6 countries. 22 Ph.D. Positions are funded in the FACETS-ITN project in the following scientific work areas: Neurobiology of Cells and Networks, Modelling of Neural Systems, Neuromorphic Hardware, Neuro-Electronic Interfaces, Computational Principles in Neural Architectures, Mechanisms of Learning and Plasticity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PACE-ITN (2015/2019)</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/project/pace-itn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/project/pace-itn/</guid>
      <description>The PACE ITN project involves over 50 researchers spread across 10 full and 5 associated partners, from academia and the private sector, established in 7 different European and Associated countries, the PACE network gathers a broad range of expertise from experimental psychology, cognitive neurosciences, brain imaging, technology and clinical sciences.
The PACE Project has received funding from the European Union’s Horizon 2020 research and innovation programme under the Marie Sklodowska-Curie grant agreement No 642961</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>