<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Grants | Novel visual computations</title>
    <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/grant/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://laurentperrinet.github.io/grant/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Grants</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>This material is presented to ensure timely dissemination of scholarly and technical work. Copyright and all rights therein are retained by authors or by other copyright holders. All persons copying this information are expected to adhere to the terms and constraints invoked by each author&#39;s copyright. In most cases, these works may not be reposted without the explicit permission of the copyright holder. 
This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 3.0 Unported License Please note that multiple distribution, publication or commercial usage of copyrighted papers included in this website would require submission of a permission request addressed to the journal in which the paper appeared. </copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/img/hulk.png</url>
      <title>Grants</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/grant/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>MesoCentre (2018/2022)</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/grant/mesocentre/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/grant/mesocentre/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the field of neuroscience, modeling has long made it possible to validate and predict theories of information processing in the neural networks that make up the brain. The recent emergence of solutions inherited from machine learning, in particular deep learning, has changed the field since 2012. One reason for the effectiveness of these methods is the amount of data analyzed but above all the ability to teach these algorithms on dedicated architectures, including graphics cards (GPUs). Indeed, this architecture allows an algorithm to be parallelized into a multitude of simple and independent subprograms that allow speed gains of around 6x to 10x to be achieved over traditional visual information processing architectures. We are now using these architectures excessively to test new image processing models - targeting applications in both neuroscience and machine learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dans le domaine des neurosciences, la modélisation a longtemps permis d&amp;rsquo;effectuer des validations et prédictions sur les théories du traitement de l&amp;rsquo;information dans les réseaux de neurones qui constitue le cerveau. L&amp;rsquo;émergence récente de solutions héritées de l&amp;rsquo;apprentissage machine, en particulier l&amp;rsquo;apprentissage profond (Deep Learning) est venu bouleverser le champ depuis 2012. Une raison de l&amp;rsquo;efficacité de ces méthodes est la quantité de données analysées mais surtout la capacité de faire apprendre ces algorithmes sur des architectures dédiées, notamment les cartes graphiques (GPU). En effet cette architecture permet de paralléliser un algorithme en une multitude de sous programmes simples et indépendants qui permettent d&amp;rsquo;atteindre des gains de vitesse de l&amp;rsquo;ordre de 6x à 10x sur des architectures classiques de traitement de l&amp;rsquo;information visuelle. Nous utilisons maintenant excessivement ces architectures pour tester de nouveaux modèles de traitement des images - en visant des applications  aussi bien aux neurosciences qu&amp;rsquo;en apprentissage machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Acknowledgement: This work was granted access to the HPC resources of Aix-Marseille Université financed by the project Equip@Meso (ANR-10-EQPX-29-01) of the program « Investissements d’Avenir » supervised by the Agence Nationale de la Recherche.»&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
