<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>facets on Novel visual computations</title>
    <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/tags/facets/</link>
    <description>Recent content in facets on Novel visual computations</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This material is presented to ensure timely dissemination of scholarly and technical work. Copyright and all rights therein are retained by authors or by other copyright holders. All persons copying this information are expected to adhere to the terms and constraints invoked by each author&#39;s copyright. In most cases, these works may not be reposted without the explicit permission of the copyright holder.
&lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Creative Commons License&#34; style=&#34;border-width:0&#34; src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/3.0/88x31.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This work is licensed under a &lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 3.0 Unported License&lt;/a&gt;
Please note that multiple distribution, publication or commercial usage of copyrighted papers included in this website would require submission of a permission request addressed to the journal in which the paper appeared.
</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://laurentperrinet.github.io/tags/facets/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2010-06-22 : CodeJamNr4</title>
      <link>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/2010-06-22_codejam-nr4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/2010-06-22_codejam-nr4/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;facets-code-jam-workshop-4&#34;&gt;FACETS Code Jam Workshop #4&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We held a CodeJam 22nd-24th June 2010, in Marseille.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://neuralensemble.org/media/images/codejam4_group_photo.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Participants&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;From the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://neuralensemble.org/meetings/CodeJam4/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of the FACETS CodeJam workshops is to catalyze open-source, collaborative software development in computational and systems neuroscience and neuroinformatics, by bringing together researchers, students and engineers to share ideas, present their work, and write code together. The general format of the workshops is to dedicate the mornings to invited and contributed talks, leaving the afternoons free for discussions and code sprints. &lt;BR&gt;
    For the 4th FACETS CodeJam, the main theme of the meeting will be workflows: what are the best practices for combining different tools (simulators, analysis tools, visualization tools, databases etc.) to ensure the efficient and reproducible flow of data and information from experiment conception to publication and archiving? &lt;BR&gt;
    (&amp;hellip;) &lt;BR&gt;
    The meeting organizers gratefully acknowledge the support of the European Union through the FACETS Project (grant no. IST-2005-15879), and the International Neuroinformatics Co-ordinating Facility (INCF). We also wish to express our great appreciation to the DyVA team at the Institut de Neurosciences Cognitives de la Méditerranée for providing us with a great location and much assistance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://neuralensemble.org/meetings/CodeJam4.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://neuralensemble.org/meetings/CodeJam4.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://neuralensemble.org/meetings/CJ4_Program_v2.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://neuralensemble.org/meetings/CJ4_Program_v2.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://facets.kip.uni-heidelberg.de/internal/jss/AttendMeeting?mI=73&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;FACETS code jam #4&lt;/a&gt;{.https}&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;featured.png&#34; alt=&#34;Affiche&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
